<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: congratulations | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/congratulations/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-06T23:09:49-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I GOT INTO CODE FELLOWS]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/05/i-got-into-code-fellows/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-05T20:54:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/05/i-got-into-code-fellows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>September 12th, 2013</p>

<h3>Official Code Fellows Acceptance</h3>

<p>I finally heard back from CodeFellows.  I&rsquo;m in!  Both Silver and Gold.</p>

<p>Yeay!!!</p>

<p><em>thud</em></p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Ready for Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/30/getting-ready-for-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-30T20:56:47-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/30/getting-ready-for-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>September 16th, 2013</p>

<h3>Acceptance</h3>

<p>The news has finally come.  I have been accepted to both silver and gold.  I am excited, pleased, terrified, and eager.  I am torn between wishing I&rsquo;d been qualified to skip silver and go straight to gold.  It would have been a nice time and money saver.  I am also relieved, in that now I know I will be fully qualified as I start each class and won&rsquo;t be running to catch up a little as I go straight into gold.  Additional huge bonus for me will be attending both bootcamps at the same time as my husband.  Sharing the commute and sharing the experience together will be, I think, a great benefit for us both.</p>

<h3>Preparing for winter</h3>

<p>Now for the big push to try to get the ranch ready for the rainy season, mostly this means spreading the contents of the compost bins on the pasture before the rain shuts down that process for the season.  Additionally, I seem to have gotten it into my head to freeze and can fruits and sauces this year. I&rsquo;ve been having fun experimenting with my new canning skills.  Thank you again to good friends who held a Jam Bee where an experienced friend taught us how to make and can berry jam.  This gives me a nice way to store my husband&rsquo;s yummy spaghetti sauce made with roma tomatoes from my garden.  I feel very domestic and accomplished.</p>

<h3>Loving my family</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ll enjoy having the time for these sorts of endeavors of love for my family while I am able.  Soon enough, I&rsquo;ll be taking care of my family using different talents.  It will be nice this winter, when I am thoroughly re-immersed in the working world, to be able to pull out some of those tasty summer offerings tucked away on a shelf, brimming with flavors from the sun.  I never really thought of myself as the back to
nature, hippy type.  But I do love feeding my family so well with local produce.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
