<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: technical history | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/technical-history/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-28T12:31:02-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My technical background]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/15/my-technical-background/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-15T22:50:35-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/15/my-technical-background</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First, some history to know where I come from, technologically.  I discovered a passion for computers in a programming class I took in high school.  I gradual route through post-high school education finally took me to the University of California at Santa Cruz.  I initally planned to major in Computer Science, but when I discovered that they had a Computer Engineering progam when I could learn all about the hardware and still take programming classes as my upper division electives, I knew I&rsquo;d found the right program for me.  Years of hard work later saw me successfully graduated and employed in the computer industry as a software tester.  I had initially planned to become a developer, but landed my first industry job at a startup that needed a tester immediately and I was the only one in their list willing to come in the very next day, a Saturday.  Yes, I had social plans, but the opportunity was not to be missed.</p>

<p>Several industry quality engineering positions later, I decided that I very much liked testing, as long as I was working very closely with the development process.  I wanted to be in on the design decisions and debug the specs (specifications) before they were implemented and it was too late.  Slowly the industry changed, turning quality engineers into SDETs and requiring automation of monolithic systems where it is hard to feel like your testing, your coding, or your opinions matter much.  I&rsquo;ve managed to avoid this side of the industry until now.  But now, it seems to be the standard.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
