<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: public speaking | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/public-speaking/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-06T16:35:49-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GeekGirlCon networking meetup]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/25/geekgirlcon-networking-meetup/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-25T23:00:35-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/25/geekgirlcon-networking-meetup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>April 11th, 2013</p>

<h3>GeekGirlCon Cocktail Connections</h3>

<p>This was the first in my networking event line up.  A meetup for the purpose of networking with other geeky women.  It seemed like a good first step to get me started on networking.  I was very nervous going into this, since this sort of thing is way outside of my comfort zone.  Ok, deep breath, I can do this.</p>

<h3>Not so bad</h3>

<p>It turned out that these are good and friendly folk.  We were all mostly new, but that helped somewhat.  I introduced myself to a number of folks and worked on those introduction sorts of conversations.  Some were more successful that others.  I&rsquo;m glad I went.  This was a good training event in how to network.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Submitted Application to Code Fellows]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/10/submitted-application-to-code-fellows/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T20:48:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/10/submitted-application-to-code-fellows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>July 26th, 2013</p>

<h3>Code Fellows</h3>

<p>Not sure where I found these folks initially.  I think I just kept stumbling over the name over and over.  It seemed like a rigorous but awesome solution to my dilemna of wanting to learn enough to break into development in the computer industry.  From what I read, it was going to be very intense, but also very effective, and with a money back guarantee if I didn&rsquo;t get a relevent industry job paying $60,000 or more.  Steep price tag though.  Really steep.  And it has been going up.  I&rsquo;d noticed that they had a women&rsquo;s only Ruby on Rails bootcamp over the summer, but I just wasn&rsquo;t quite ready to commit when the deadline came (about a week after I&rsquo;d heard about them, I think).  But now, I think I&rsquo;m ready, so&hellip;</p>

<h3>Preliminary application</h3>

<p>Today I finally took a big and scary step.  I wrote and submitted my application to CodeFellows for the Ruby on Rails bootcamp this late fall.  I took my time and gave thoughtful responses and felt pretty good about it.  Less than an hour later, I already had a response.  On a Friday late afternoon!</p>

<p>I had made it to the next round of the Bootcamp Application.</p>

<h3>Ruby on Rails bootcamp application assignment</h3>

<p>Now, I just have to:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Put together a short YouTube video introducing myself and explaining something technical related to programming.</p></li>
<li><p>Submit a best-foot-forward code sample.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>I am elated to have made it to the next round.  I am also eager and nervous about the next requirements.</p>

<p>Oooo.  I think I have a cool idea.  Off to see what I can work out.  Looks like the family will need to share me with technology this weekend.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
