<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: NorWesCon | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/norwescon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-28T00:58:56-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remembering Ruby]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/10/remembering-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-10T22:14:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/10/remembering-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Remembering a nudge towards Ruby Koans that I&rsquo;d been given by a friend and colleague a couple years back and the fun I had exploring that, I did a bit of idle research investigating online learning resources for Ruby.  I stumbled upon CodeAcademy&hellip;</p>

<p>&hellip;</p>

<p>Spring brought with it one of the local science fiction conventions.  There were several panels that got me thingking about women in technology, networking within my industry, and how to re-find my passion in technology.  I decided it was time to pick back up my long abandoned pursuit of programming and to start networking with other women in technology for mutual support and growth.  I had dabbled with Ruby a couple of years ago at the recommendation of a friend and colleague, so I decided on Ruby on Rails as a good and enjoyable path toward my goal.  I joined several relevent local meetup groups and then I learned of She&rsquo;s Geeky 13, Seattle.  Attending this un-conference made all the difference in the world and confirmed the wisdom of my ideas.  I finalized my plan for re-purposing my career with the attendant studying, learning, networking needed  over the next several months to change my career from being a 20 year software tester, to being a newby Ruby on Rails developer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NorWesCon]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/05/norwescon/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-05T22:57:51-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/05/norwescon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, back to the plan to renew that passion and prepare for my reentry into the workforce.  This spring, I went to our local annual literary convention and attended several panels about women in STEM (science, technology, engineering, math) and women networking with women.  Most of my social connections previously have been with men, so networking with women was a bit frightening.  But, I needed to get out more and freshen my networking skills as a preparation for interviewing so I plunged forward.  I chose a couple of venues to start with.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
