<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: DevChix | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/devchix/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-06T23:09:49-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Networking with female developers]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/20/codechix/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-20T23:06:42-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/20/codechix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I chose a couple of venues to start with, both online and in person.</p>

<h3>DevChix</h3>

<p>Online, there is DevChix.  This is a women&rsquo;s only group where I find women encouraging other women in technology, talking to each other about various social or technical challenges in the industry, and almost anything else a woman who programs might like to discuss.  I highly recommend this Google group.</p>

<h3>CodeChix</h3>

<p>I must give a huge shout out to Shaili Guru of the Seattle chapter of CodeChix.  I started out just attending a little C# introduction held at the library.  I have since attended a number of events held by CodeChix and have had my best networking experiences there.  I&rsquo;ve also met some of my favorite companies with whom I later enjoyed excellent interviews at CodeChix events.  This group seems mostly based in Silicon Valley, with a good chapter in Seattle, a website, and meetup groups by city.</p>

<h3>Women Who Code, Seattle</h3>

<p>This international group started in 2011 and has been spreading.  The Seattle chapter started in November 2013 and already is approaching 400 members.  Such a neat experience walking into a room of 60 women, all of whom write code.  They have a website, a newsletter, and meetup groups by city.  I&rsquo;ve found the newsletter very useful to discover events I haven&rsquo;t found anywhere else, such as one of Google&rsquo;s Women in Technology events.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
