<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: CodeAcademy | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/codeacademy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-06T23:09:49-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CodeAcademy]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/18/codeacademy/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-18T23:09:43-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/18/codeacademy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Ruby?</h3>

<p>Remembering a nudge towards Ruby Koans that I&rsquo;d been given by a friend and colleague a couple years back, I also remembered the fun I had exploring Ruby and how easy Ruby made things.  Ruby doesn&rsquo;t have the pain of memory allocation and pointers and string manipulation pain.  This seemed like something to investigate further, so I did a bit of research investigating online learning resources for Ruby.</p>

<h3>CodeAcademy</h3>

<p>I found CodeAcademy and spent most of April and May working my way through thier Ruby, JavaScript, and JQuery offerings.  Their lessons are pretty basic introductions, but are a fun introduction and free.  I hadn&rsquo;t really meant to do the JS and JQuery lessons, but the Ruby lessons were broken for a while.  I enjoyed the gamification of the coding lessons, where I could earn a personal high score in Points Today, Day Streak, Total Points, and Badges Completed.</p>

<h3>Coding!</h3>

<p>I was rapidly starting to believe that Ruby on Rails may well be a good and enjoyable start along my path towards my goal.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RailsTutorial]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/05/railstutorial/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-05T22:29:54-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/05/railstutorial</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The month of May found me finishing up CodeAcademy and looking for something new.</p>

<h3>RailsTutorial</h3>

<p>Remembering some advice from the Seattle Rails event, I looked into Michael Hartl&rsquo;s online RailsTutorial.  I&rsquo;d been learning Ruby all this time, which is a programming language.  A particularly high level and weakly typed language.  Rails is a framework that is written in Ruby.  What I had not realized before now is that I&rsquo;d been using Rails back at my last job and so was already rather familiar with it.</p>

<h3>GitHub</h3>

<p>I also started my GitHub repository as a result of working through RailsTutorial.  I had no idea at the time just how important and heavily used that repo would become.  It makes me smile, looking back.</p>

<h3>StackOverflow</h3>

<p>I took about 2 months to work through RailsTutorial.  I really took my time so I would fully understand things as well as trying to work through the various exercises.  I first became familiar with StackOverflow at this time, since occasionally, syntax changes in newer versions of Ruby/Rails would cause proplems.  Goodness have I ended up becoming familiar with Stack Overflow over the last year as a Go To place for finding solutions to problems.  So far, I haven&rsquo;t answered a question nor posed a question of my own.  Impostor Syndrome or perfectionism has kept me from doing it so far as I want to be sure to get it just right.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
