<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-28T00:30:53-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An introduction]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/27/an-introduction/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-27T22:49:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/27/an-introduction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Intro post
by GeekyMamaMare
May 8, 2013</p>

<p>My new adventure begins.</p>

<p>My name is Susan Prestage.  I&rsquo;ve been a quality engineer in the computer industry for 20 years.  In the summer of 2011, my dream job fell through my hands and I was left devastated.  I quickly realized that I was far to emotionally fragile for the moment and needed to take some time away from the industry to recover from my heart ache.  A year passed and I refreshed my resume and leapt back into the job seeking pool.  I have been fortunate in the past that each job came along just as it was needed, usually through networking, and generally right along the lines of where I wanted my career to go.  This time was a different experience.  None of the jobs available seemed to be a good fit for my skills or my experience.  I also was beginning to discover a lack of motivation in my search.  It was as if my passion for technology and computers was missing.  I took a bit of time to figure out my priorities and what made me eager to go to work in the morning, only to discover that I really wasn&rsquo;t seeing anything available in the job market that made me eager to leave my family, my son, my ranch, and my horses in the morning.  My new goals started to come clear.  I wanted to renew my passion for technology such that I could find a company to contribute to that made me as eager to head to the office in the morning as I was to return to my beloved ranch in the evening.</p>

<p>Ok, good goal.  Now to develop a plan to take me towards that goal.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who Am I?]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/25/who-am-i/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-25T23:43:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/25/who-am-i</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<h2>  OUTLINE</h2>

<p>Title: &ldquo;Who are you?&rdquo; and &ldquo;What do you want?&rdquo;</p>

<ol>
<li><p>intro - name, handle</p></li>
<li><p>I am mare</p></li>
<li><p>I am mama</p></li>
<li><p>I am geeky</p></li>
<li><p>I am becoming a ruby on rails dev</p></li>
</ol>


<hr />

<h2> FIRST DRAFT</h2>

<p>&ldquo;Who are you?&rdquo; and &ldquo;What do you want?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Hello old friends.  Hello new friends.  Hello colleagues.  Hello young learners.  Hello respected professionals.  I am the GeekyMamaMare.  Welcome to my blog.  Please enjoy sharing my journey of re-discovering my passion in technology and re-directing (re-purposing?) my career from software testing to software development.  A wordy intro statement indeed, but very relevant to my journey as you will see in time.  Let&rsquo;s start by looking at who I am now.  The most important aspects of my life all fall into three categories.  My horses, my family, and my geekiness.  Everything I do in life ties into at least one of these.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been involved with horses my entire life.  They inspire me.  I love them deeply and their presence in my life is one of the foundations of my happiness and life satisfaction.  After hoping and planning from my early to mid-teens, I finally have my dream ranch and my horse breeding program.  I am working toward breeding honest, clever, and well-moving young horses that will, I hope, become that long sought after equine partner for the aspiring rider looking for just the right equine friend.  A challenging goal.  Intelligent horses can be a wonderful challenge to raise, but very rewarding as well.  My careful breeding choices are taking care of the intelligence and athleticism.  The daily focus of to raise and train up the youngsters in a loving but disciplined environment to produce and nurture their good and willing nature.</p>

<p>I am blessed with a wonderful family.  Most of all, by my son.  I am absolutely biased as any mother would be.  I find my son to be beautiful, very bright, energetic, loving and kind, gentle, a great adventuring partner, and a delight to watch learn and grow.  I am also incredibly lucky in that he seems to share my love of horses and things geeky.  I felt like I won the baby lottery when he was born back in 2009 and have felt that even more so as the years pass.  Certainly, he goes through the various challenges and foibles of every youngster, but I still feel like we have an easier time of it than most, and am very grateful to be so blessed.  I am also fortunate, especially in this journey of re-discovery, to have an understanding and supportive family.  It can be very difficult to change a career in midlife, especially with all the learning, studying, and growing that are involved in that process.  They were very worried about me as I realized I&rsquo;d lost my passion in technology.  And now they are encouraging, patient, and supportive as I learn and grow.  It can be very hard for the family at such a time.  I am so glad that they are behind me all the way.  I am very lucky.  I could be making these changes without their support.</p>

<p>In some ways, I was very sheltered while growing up in California&rsquo;s San Joaquin valley.  I had my horses, my books, a few friends, and a hugely active imagination.  I was mostly busy in my own world of pretend, but not too much so.  I was an adequate student without trying.  I was somewhat social as well as somewhat athletic.  I was also a voracious reader.  This last was probably what led me to declare myself &ldquo;weird&rdquo; in ninth grade.  I&rsquo;m not sure what I was going for at the time, but in hindsight, I was very right.  It was hard to be interested in elclectic, odd, and alternative things in the area where I grew up, since mainstream culture was almost all that was available.  But libraries were a good friend to me and my active imagination combined with new ideas and worlds and creatures from books allowed me to explore my &ldquo;weirdness&rdquo; or what I now call my geekiness.  As an adult, I moved to the San Francisco Bay Area and eventually to Santa Cruz where I found many other geeky people and interests to pursue.  I discovered Sci Fi/Fantasy conventions, the SCA, gaming, electronics, and so much more.  I worked hard at the local community college getting my core classes out of the way, then transferred to UC Santa Cruz, where I discovered that instead of majoring in programming, I could major in computer engineering, playing with chips, resistors, capacitors, and wiring, while taking programming classes as upper division electives.  So much fun!  I am still an electronics hobbiest and delight in pulling out my old soldering gun.</p>

<p>When just beginning my career with computers, there was a huge hiring freeze all through Silicon Valley.  This made finding a programming job very difficult for someone still in college.  I got an opportunity, but it started me on the path of software testing instead of programming.  I was initially a little unsatisfied, but eventually grew to love breaking software.  This satisfied me for a long while.  But eventually it was not enough.  I eventually landed my dream job in testing.  I was working with a product that I respected, with technology I enjoyed, with colleagues that were fun and challenging to work with, creating a product that was making a real difference in the world.  But it was a very small company.  And small companies must grow.  And when small companies grow, they change.  And often, those changes create a culture and a company mission that was not what it once was.  Parting with my dream job in the end was painful and made me quesion myself, my abilities, and my passion in technology entirely.  I spent that next year pursuing interests around my family and my horses in order to recover, since I was in no condition to market myself to a new company.  I eventually found my balance again, updated and polished up the ole resume, and dove into the job search.  I was ready to return to work.  I thought.  But as the weeks and then months passed, none of the job listings seemed right.  They were looking for skills I neither had nor wanted, or were working on things that held no interest.  I felt my passion for technology falling to the wayside, in the face of the drab, the mundane, the stultifying.  It was a low moment indeed.</p>

<p>Thus begins my journey.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Do I Want]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/20/what-do-i-want/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-20T21:19:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/20/what-do-i-want</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An old friend from my old Santa Cruz days visited over Thanksgiving.  I was pretty uncomfortable in my own skin at the time and had been been feeling like I didn&rsquo;t have anyone I felt like I could turn to.  You see, I&rsquo;m a very strong personality.  Small surprise there, I know.  But what this ends up meaning is that for all I seem very strong and able on the outside, I have a lot of doubt and weakness on the inside.  I feel like so many people look up to me (I still am perplexed by this), that none of them feel to me like they are strong enough and have the perpective to be someone I can lean one and turn to when I&rsquo;m feeling week and in need of someone who sees me as just a person.  With faults and foibles, but loves me deeply and can give me that support that only a friend who has known you for many years can give you.  The kind of support that sometimes involves a boot in the arse.  Thank you, dear Kallie.</p>

<p>She reminded me of the things I find important.  And that my weakness was part of my strength and definitely part of my appeal.  She showed me the beginnings of the support that women can give one another.  And I started to discover some of the strength found from the support of other engineering women.  She reminded me, through many delightfully geeky conversations of my love for engineering, right down to the ones and zeros of circuit design.  To be sure I&rsquo;d learned the lesson, this valued friend sent me a LED clock engineering kit for my birthday in the beginning of 2013.  It wasn&rsquo;t very long before I took the time to start soldering the pieces of that clock.  So. Much. Fun.</p>

<p>Hey.  There it is.  My joy in engineering.  Still there, without a doubt.  OK, so now what&hellip;?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My technical background]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/15/my-technical-background/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-15T22:50:35-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/15/my-technical-background</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First, some history to know where I come from, technologically.  I discovered a passion for computers in a programming class I took in high school.  I gradual route through post-high school education finally took me to the University of California at Santa Cruz.  I initally planned to major in Computer Science, but when I discovered that they had a Computer Engineering progam when I could learn all about the hardware and still take programming classes as my upper division electives, I knew I&rsquo;d found the right program for me.  Years of hard work later saw me successfully graduated and employed in the computer industry as a software tester.  I had initially planned to become a developer, but landed my first industry job at a startup that needed a tester immediately and I was the only one in their list willing to come in the very next day, a Saturday.  Yes, I had social plans, but the opportunity was not to be missed.</p>

<p>Several industry quality engineering positions later, I decided that I very much liked testing, as long as I was working very closely with the development process.  I wanted to be in on the design decisions and debug the specs (specifications) before they were implemented and it was too late.  Slowly the industry changed, turning quality engineers into SDETs and requiring automation of monolithic systems where it is hard to feel like your testing, your coding, or your opinions matter much.  I&rsquo;ve managed to avoid this side of the industry until now.  But now, it seems to be the standard.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remembering Ruby]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/10/remembering-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-10T22:14:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/10/remembering-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Remembering a nudge towards Ruby Koans that I&rsquo;d been given by a friend and colleague a couple years back and the fun I had exploring that, I did a bit of idle research investigating online learning resources for Ruby.  I stumbled upon CodeAcademy&hellip;</p>

<p>&hellip;</p>

<p>Spring brought with it one of the local science fiction conventions.  There were several panels that got me thingking about women in technology, networking within my industry, and how to re-find my passion in technology.  I decided it was time to pick back up my long abandoned pursuit of programming and to start networking with other women in technology for mutual support and growth.  I had dabbled with Ruby a couple of years ago at the recommendation of a friend and colleague, so I decided on Ruby on Rails as a good and enjoyable path toward my goal.  I joined several relevent local meetup groups and then I learned of She&rsquo;s Geeky 13, Seattle.  Attending this un-conference made all the difference in the world and confirmed the wisdom of my ideas.  I finalized my plan for re-purposing my career with the attendant studying, learning, networking needed  over the next several months to change my career from being a 20 year software tester, to being a newby Ruby on Rails developer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NorWesCon]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/05/norwescon/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-05T22:57:51-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/05/norwescon</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, back to the plan to renew that passion and prepare for my reentry into the workforce.  This spring, I went to our local annual literary convention and attended several panels about women in STEM (science, technology, engineering, math) and women networking with women.  Most of my social connections previously have been with men, so networking with women was a bit frightening.  But, I needed to get out more and freshen my networking skills as a preparation for interviewing so I plunged forward.  I chose a couple of venues to start with.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CodeAcademy]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/30/codeacademy/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-30T23:09:43-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/30/codeacademy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finally got going with CodeAcademy.  Have been very active since signing up.  I seem to recall thinking about it for a week or two before I was ready to comit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GeekGirlCon Cocktail Connections]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/25/geekgirlcon-cocktail-connections/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-25T23:00:35-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/25/geekgirlcon-cocktail-connections</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>GeekGirlCon meetup: This is a meetup for the purpose of networking with other geeky women.  It seemed like a good first step to get me started on networking.  It turned out that these are good and friendly folk.  We were all mostly new, but that helped somewhat.  I introduced myself to a number of folks and worked on those introduction sorts of conversations.  Some were more successful that others.  I&rsquo;m glad I went.  This was a good training event.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CodeChix]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/20/codechix/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-20T23:06:42-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/20/codechix</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  Found CodeChix, probably through DevChix (first noticed 4/4/13), attended intro to C# (pt2) by Shaili Guru</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seattle Rails Educational/Networking Meetup]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/15/seattle-rails-educational-slash-networking-meetup/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-15T23:04:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/15/seattle-rails-educational-slash-networking-meetup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Seattle Rails Educational/Networking Meetup:  This was an evening-long event with two technical talks, dinner, and networking.  I was pretty nervous going into this, since my programming skills are rusty at best, and I am completely new to Ruby.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[She's Geeky]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/10/shes-geeky/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-10T23:28:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/10/shes-geeky</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RailsTutorial]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/05/railstutorial/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-05T22:29:54-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/05/railstutorial</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>5/8 Joined GitHub &amp; started rails tutorial
5/8-7/6 RailsTutorial</p>

<p>  Finished CodeAcademy (sometime during RailsTutorial, 5/8-7/6)  Finished sometime 5/18 or later.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Codechix Ruby on Rails hacking session]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/25/Codechix+Ruby+on+Rails+hacking+session/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-25T22:33:05-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/25/Codechix Ruby on Rails hacking session</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>7/14  First ruby/rails ladies meetup (thanks to codechix and Shaili Guru)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[family summer vacation]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/20/family-summer-vacation/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-20T22:37:45-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/20/family-summer-vacation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>7/17-21 Summer family vacation</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Submitted Application to Code Fellows]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/10/submitted-application-to-code-fellows/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T20:48:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/10/submitted-application-to-code-fellows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I finally took a big and scary step.  I wrote and submitted my application to CodeFellows for the Ruby on Rails bootcamp this late fall.  I took my time and gave thoughtful responses and felt pretty good about it.  Less than an hour later, I already had a response.  On a Friday late afternoon!</p>

<p>I had made it to the next round of the Bootcamp Application.</p>

<p>Now, I just have to:</p>

<pre><code>1. Put together a short YouTube video introducing myself and explaining something technical related to programming.

2. Submit a best-foot-forward code sample.
</code></pre>

<p>I am elated to have made it to the next round.  I am also eager and nervous about the next requirements.  Oooo.  I think I
have a cool idea.  Off to see what I can work out.  Looks like the family will need to share me with technology this weekend.</p>

<p>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preliminary Code Fellows Application Accepted]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/05/code-fellows-application-accepted/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-05T20:50:02-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/05/code-fellows-application-accepted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Code sample</h3>

<p>Code sample nearly complete.  I&rsquo;ve been checking into github all along the way.  It makes me feel a bit vulnerable to put the code out there while I&rsquo;m still working on it, but I will wait until I finish before I submit it officially.  Perhaps seeing how I put it together will give them more of a good impression that not.  I hope so.  I find myself being quite self conscious of my code.  My husband asked to take a look at it and has been pouring through it all afternoon&hellip;talk about self consciouness inducing.  Whew!</p>

<h3>Guessing my level</h3>

<p>I am very interested to see if I will qualify for the Silver or the Gold level of boot camp.  Gold means that I can skip the first month-long class and just take the second one.  It will be a lovely savings in time and money, so I am doing my best and we&rsquo;ll see how I rank.  The savings would be nice, but I am more interested in finding out where I place.  I find that sort of metric to be very interesting.  I&rsquo;m guessing that I rank about week 3 of 4 in the first month.  That would still mean that I need to take the first class too, but I&rsquo;ll have a very thorough review for the first week or so.  All to the good.  I could use a good portfolio of code snippets I&rsquo;ve written stored up on github for those code submissions that I&rsquo;ve been told companies are more interested in these days.</p>

<h3>Coding at the lake</h3>

<p>I had a lovely afternoon early this week having a picnic at Rattlesnake Lake with son, husband, and friend.  Perfect weather, not too hot, not too cold.  The others frolicked in the water, as I sat in the shade working out some snarls in my code.  Got all the code fixed that was broken.  Implemented additional code, some even worked right off.  All is unit tested.  Happy family.  Happy mama.</p>

<h3>Blueberries!</h3>

<p>Took another break yesterday morning to take son, husband, and friend blueberry picking at the local farm.  We came home with 16 pounds!  Reaped wonderful rewards at 2am while burning the midnight oil coding, as the smell of blueberry crumble wafted upstairs from the ambitious efforts of my brother&rsquo;s girlfriend.  Oh joy!  The merits of diligence to my work as well as taking time with my family.  I must be doing something right.</p>

<h3>Wrapup</h3>

<p>And now it is time to get back to figuring out that intro video.  I&rsquo;m taking a break from the code for the moment.  I&rsquo;ve done a lot over the last 24 hours, so I should give it a little bit of a rest before I leap in and implement that UI.</p>

<p>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coding at the Festival]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/30/coding-at-the-festival/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-30T20:52:40-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/30/coding-at-the-festival</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is a beautiful, partly cloudy afternoon at the Festival at Mt Si here in my little home town.  I am ensconced on a blanket on the grass, leaning against a large tree in a thoroughly shady spot.  There is a nice breeze.  The band playing nearby is a pleasant backdrop to the pleasant murmur of my neighbors and their children enjoying a lovely summer afternoon.</p>

<p>My free range son is running around, encountering friends, exhausting himself in the bouncy houses, and experiencing the thrill of a large climbing wall where a harness and helmet are required.  I feel pleasantly steeped in the community experience today.  I have chosen the right place to raise my family and spend the rest of my life.  The beauty of my surroundings is staggering.</p>

<p>And now, back to some more ruby coding.  I&rsquo;ve got to hurry up and finish that code for round two of the CodeFellows application.  I&rsquo;ve got a fun idea that has come together very well, so I am excited to get it ready for submission.</p>

<p>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seattle Girl Geek Dinner - meet Code Fellows]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/20/seattle-girl-geek-dinner-meet-code-fellows/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-20T22:39:39-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/20/seattle-girl-geek-dinner-meet-code-fellows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>8/20  Seattle Girl Geek Dinner, sponsored by Code Fellows</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code Fellows follow up application]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/15/code-fellows-follow-up-application/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-15T22:41:20-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/15/code-fellows-follow-up-application</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>timeline:9/8-9/9 CodeFellows follow up application (3 apps over 4 days, Yikes!!!)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I GOT INTO CODE FELLOWS]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/10/i-got-into-code-fellows/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-10T20:54:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/10/i-got-into-code-fellows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Official Code Fellows Acceptance</p>

<p>I finally heard back from CodeFellows.  I&rsquo;m in!  Both Silver and Gold.</p>

<p>Yeay!</p>

<p>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
