<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-27T21:18:11-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 23 of Code Fellows Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/11/06/day-23-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-06T13:55:15-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/11/06/day-23-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wednesday the 6th of November, 2013  8:02 am</p>

<p>  So, late last week, one of our instructors was commenting about how one of
the founders of seattle.rb, Ryan Davis, had been bugging him to make
attending the next seattle.rb meetup and presenting either a lightning talk
or our class projects a required assignment for everyone in class. Thank you,
Ryan. /sarcasm
  Well, Ivan kindly did not make this mandatory, yet, seeing the wisdom, in
spite of my fears (and I assure you, they were plenty), my partner and I
presented our class project  So the next day, I got on to the seattle.rb site
and signed us up  The attendance was enourmous, apparently about three times
their norm. But that&rsquo;s what you get when you nag CodeFellows and the Ada
Academy to attend; well, there&rsquo;s a lot of us.
  It was absolutely delightful to meet the women from the Ada Academy. The
Ada Academy is a year-long program for women who want to be developers but
have little to absolutely no experience in most cases. I got to bring out
several of my pet hobbyhorses, much to their entertainment; impostor syndrome,
the hard work and hard won skill that is networking (meaning going to these
meetings and interacting with <em>gasp</em> humans. New ones! That you don&rsquo;t already
know!). It was flattering to realize that listening in the background was
Carrie Miller, one of the founders/teachers/somethingorother of the Ada
Academy. Carrie is a strong leader for women in technology. Her name and face
keep coming across my screen, usually through devchicks, but other places,
too, where good conversations are happening about the challenges women face
in technology, particularly the computer industry. It was a pleasure to later
meet her and speak with her further about the Ada Academy.
  The presentation went well.  The Adas in particular were a very appriciative
audience and took the time later to say how much they enjoyed it.  I went home
exhausted, it being several hours after my usual bedtime, but feeling strong
in the path I&rsquo;ve chosen and where it&rsquo;s taking me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 20, last day of Silver. I made it to GOLD!]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/11/01/i-made-it-to-gold/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-01T15:48:17-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/11/01/i-made-it-to-gold</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  Oh.  Em.  Gee.
  We made it.
  Listening around the work tables at CodeFellows this week, as we were all
working on our class projects, I started hearing other people saying little
things that suggested to me that I was not the only one scared, behind, and
terrified that I was not going to pass Silver. They did not say it in so many
words, but I heard a lot of worry. Of course, what I saw when I looked at
their screens was a level of polish that made made my knees quake with, yeah,
you guessed it, Impostor Syndrome. But the words I was hearing, the furrowed
brows I was seeing, the increasingly frazzled appearances, suggested to me
that these, my peers, might be in the same boat I was.
  Today was the day. One PM was code freeze. Ivan sounded the gong at
exactly one, over and over, and shooed us all downstairs to present Our
Projects. I made sure, over the last two days, to keep an eye on the look
and feel of our project, knowing that just functionality is important, too,
but dropping design on the floor would be a mistake. I came into today very
nervous, but a little bit hopeful, because I was proud of our little site. It
looked good. It made me feel good to look at it. And that helped, giving me
just that tiniest bit of courage with which I stepped forward and presented&hellip;
first. <em>cue dramatic music</em> The presentation went well. I felt good and
confidant about what I was speaking of. My partner was the same. I had enough
to show off that I didn&rsquo;t even cover everything. I talked knowledgely about
the design decisions we made. And humourously about points of pain, confusion,
and trouble. And my audience seemed engaged and interested. I finished up
feeling&hellip; pleased. And excited. And exhausted. The other presentations of my
fellows seemed comperable in areas of strength, areas of weakness, areas of
pain, and areas of joyful technological discovery. All different, as different
people think differently and have different interests. But my fellow
bootcampers finally felt like peers. We had suffered together and we had all,
to a one, emerged triumphant.
  There was a social afterwards. With the usual libations, offered as we
shuffled desks around, since another class had just completed and a new one
had just started. The comaradarie and exhuberant energy, as well as the
occasional flat affect of mental and physical exhaustion abounded. I felt an
equal with these twenty other people at last. Even as recently as yesterday,
I would not quite have felt comfortable tapping any one of them for technical
help. Now, I feel like I could speak up at a tablefull and say &lsquo;Hey, does
anyone know how to help with this?&rsquo; Not the sort of thing I do easily. So this
is a big point of growth for me. And a warm relief.
  I still feel like I could take a month between silver and gold to finish and
wrap up all the learnings and projects and code samples that I want to write.
And I will, but it looks like it will be <em>after</em> gold.
  YAY I MADE IT TO GOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOLD.
  And now, as I commute home, in the autumn dusk, I bask in the beauty of the
random patterns of the clouds, the soft colors of the sunset, framing the
beautiful spectacle of Mount Rainer, and enjoy this moment of triumph and
peace before I leap into it all again on Monday.
  And now I go home to spend a lovely weekend with son, family, ranch, and
sleep.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 19 of Code Fellows Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/31/day-19-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-31T14:08:54-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/31/day-19-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> <em>said in a measuredly quiet voice</em>
  don&rsquo;t.  panic.
  I feel like I&rsquo;m so far behind that the natural human tendancy makes me want
to panic. It makes me want to panic, makes me want to dither, makes me want
to run screaming off into the night.
  I can&rsquo;t do that. It is too important that I stay the course, that I stay on
task.
  (yay carpools)
  I&rsquo;ve thought of some additional resources at my fingertips, and I&rsquo;m going to
start using those more, as well. And the important thing is that I don&rsquo;t let
that gibbering thing inside me take over.  Instead, I need to see what I&rsquo;ve
done, identify the piece I don&rsquo;t understand, wrap it up and put it aside, and
move on to the next thing. I need to stare at the screen reading documentation
less; it&rsquo;s not getting me very far. A little of it, certainly, but after the
third reading, I should start questioning. Code School&rsquo;s Rails for Zombies and
the RailCasts have a lot of good resoures. Taking a half or even an hour out
to learn more through one of those means won&rsquo;t take a lot away from what I&rsquo;m
accomplishing and can instead help me go forward by leaps and bounds. If I&rsquo;d
only pursued that a bit sooner, I&rsquo;d be a lot further along. Ah well, the
perfection of hindsight.</p>

<p>  I learned long ago to just keep putting one foot in front of the other, so
 that, at least, if you do fall, you&rsquo;ll fall in the correct direction. And
 that&rsquo;s making progress, too, right?</p>

<p> I&rsquo;m at the point where I&rsquo;m thinking code almost every minute of the day. I
chew on it in my dreams, I wake up wanting to sit down at my computer and
work on this or that. And I go to bed early with my son exausted and wishing
I had more resources. The whole family is showing signs of the draining
fatigue from this amazing experience. The price is very high for all of us,
but we are all committed and pulling together for the benefits to us all will
be enduring and worth it. And to be honest, the day-by-day experience is worth
it.  Exhausting as hell, but worth it.  And I remember that, most of the time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 13 of Code Fellows Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/23/day-13-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-23T13:50:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/23/day-13-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  I sacrifices sleeping in last night.  Well, not last night, but this
morning.  That&rsquo;s my story and I&rsquo;m sticking to it.
  I&rsquo;m still feeling dreadfully behind, which is to say I&rsquo;m still one week
behind.  Just like last week, when I was&hellip; one week behind.  Which means I&rsquo;m
not falling futher behind. There&rsquo;s some merit there. There are fewer and
fewer questions coming up in class lecture. The questions also seem
entirely based around the most current material. During my early morning
midnght oil burning, I came to the suspicion that far more of my classmates
are just as thoroughly behind and are feeling just as awkward about asking
questions as a result. Mostly I don&rsquo;t have a question for my instructors
because as I am progressing, I no sooner come up with a question than I
shortly discover the answer and move on to the next bit of learning.  Repeat,
slowly, a lot. I feel pretty good about the things I&rsquo;m learning, but then
the instructors asks one of those questions in class. One of those perfect
interview questions.  Something very fundamental to the understanding to
the understanding of Ruby or Rails or object-oriented programming, and I
watch the entire class flail helplessly, along with myself, as we struggle
for the words or concepts and a means to express them.
  They told us early on that they did not select us for the class because of
how smart we were.  We were chosen for this class because of how hard we work
and how hard we try. OH BOY do I hope that&rsquo;s true.  If it is, then I will make
it through.  Somehow.  One step at a time.  If not, well, I was doomed from
the outset.  So, no need to stress, just need to do.  And do.  And do.
  And maybe catch up on a little sleep this weekend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 12 of Code Fellows Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/22/day-12-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-22T17:03:22-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/22/day-12-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  Still behind, but finding my rhythm.</p>

<p>  I&rsquo;m starting to find my balance with both the work and trying to keep up
with the basic things, you know, like eating, sleeping, clean clothes, that
sort of thing. All my spare time, and there isn&rsquo;t much, is for my family and
my little boy. We all seem to be doing all right, but I think he&rsquo;s paying the
highest price. It is hard for a child to, when they have enjoyed the luxury of
their parents home for nearly their first five years of life, now have ALL
of that change. To have mama working, to have papa working, to have uncle
working, and only one at home supporting the rest of us.</p>

<p>  In class, I feel like I&rsquo;m always behind, but I still feel like I&rsquo;m learning
very effective, and getting everything implemented successfully, but the
going, while thorough, is still slow.</p>

<p>  The good news is that the class project, where I&rsquo;m collaborating with
someone else, is something my husband and I have been wanting to do for a
very long time.  It&rsquo;s an idea that has been developing for a couple of years
now, and it ends up being so well tailored for this class as a demonstration
of our skills that I am a bit startled in just how appropriate it is. This
also means YAY! something to be ahead on, and we are. If we can keep up that
pattern, I think we may be able to catch up on everything.</p>

<p>  The class is still, as we like to call it at home, &lsquo;drinking from the
informational firehose&rsquo;. And it is hard not to choke. It is important to keep
panic at bay with good eating habits, lots of sleep, and stopping to take a
breath now and then.  To that end, this last weekend, I took my family to
GeekGirlCon. But husband and I spent as much time as we could with our noses
in our laptops. The environment was both distracting and encouraging. I got to
share with several people what CodeFellows was, since my costume was the same
professional wardrobe that I wear every day to class with my CodeFellows
t-shirt under my dress coat.</p>

<p>  I&rsquo;ve been to a number of conventions. Mostly science fiction, ComicCon,
WorldCon, only one or two professional conventions.  And this con was
unique. I have never felt so welcomed and so encouraged by every person I
met. I have also never seen that many women all getting their geek on.
Teaching.  Learning.  Encouraging.  Enthusing.  And all of them happy to
share. I have always undervalued the power of women working together and
supporting one another. Part of this journey is learning is learning how
important that is. And why I want to seek it out.  For myself and to nurture
it in others. I will not be missing another GeekGirlCon, and it is only in its
third year.  What an amazing force for good this convention is and will be.
I can only imagine that this convention is for geekdom what the Grace Hopper
Conference is for STEM.  I hope next year to attend Grace Hopper to find out
for myself.</p>

<p>Blog Notes: I tried to take the time during my commute daily to simply admire
autumn&rsquo;s beauty dripping its colors through the trees. The mists drift over
the waterways, sometimes shrouding my valley in white. And then a spear of
sunlight pierces the mists, striking in its contrast.s</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 4 of Code Fellows Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/10/day-4-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-10T19:47:42-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/10/day-4-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the middle of the afternoon lab, fighting with things that are not working.  I have experienced one of the typical problems for women in STEM.  We are simply not heard.  9 students all working with an instructor, trying to work together to get us all through a difficult issue.  Two of my male classmates are starting to have success.  I ask them questions several times.  I say their names.  But not once do they look up or hear me.  Note, they are the two people closest to me.  One is RIGHT next to me.  One is in front of me.</p>

<p>I finally give up on the entire experience entirely.  I sit up straight, eyes forward, smiling slightly, hands folded on the table.  You know the position.  It is the one we are taught when we first start school.  The one that all the girls do and all the boys blow off.  After several more minutes of being ignored, which I expected really since I was mostly trying to regain my composure, I finally lose it and step away to sob my heart out in the bathroom.  I finally (sorta) put myself together and head back.  I see the two men leave the room in triumph, having succeeded where the rest of us are still struggling.</p>

<p>I sit back down.  Still unable to get anywhere, nor do I have the concentration to try at this point.  I start this post to get down this feeling.  And have just run back to the bathroom, unable to hold it together any more.  My face is now beet red and my eyes are puffy.</p>

<p>Why are women not even heard!?</p>

<p>Two women in a class of 21.  I understand very well why they have a women only bootcamp.  How I wish I took that one instead.  I fear dearly that this was all a very expensive mistake.  I want to never ask technical help from ANY man ever again.  Why should I bother.  I&rsquo;ll just be dismisse anyway.  It happened just last night with my own (male) housemates, so why should I expect any better treatment than I get at home.  And my housemates are self proclaimed feminists!</p>

<p>Ok, cleaning up to go try again.</p>

<p>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 3 of Code Fellows Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/09/day-3-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-09T08:59:42-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/09/day-3-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>8 am, October 9th, 2013
  They told us the first day not to stay up late doing our work. Get up early, sure, but don&rsquo;t stay up late. It
was Day 2 of bootcamp, and I already felt like I was struggling with the load. I stayed up until 1 am, I got it all done, and then I started Day 3 four hours later.</p>

<p>  In those early morning hours today at home, I broke down and lost it. I&rsquo;m scared that I&rsquo;m going to struggle and
try and not be able to learn enough, quickly enough, to get through bootcamp. CodeFellows is a fellowship of professionals and I&rsquo;m scared that they&rsquo;re going to take away my t-shirt. And what I mean by that is if I am struggling so much after only two days, how can it be that I belong in this class of amazing learners.</p>

<p>  And so I will document this struggle and I will share my pain with you. Because, dammit, if I can get through
this and succeed you can, too.</p>

<p>  Now if I can just hold it together long enough to get through Day 3 of class.  One day at a time.</p>

<p>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</p>

<p>  NOTE Meticulous attention to detail may be setting me up to lose.
  NOTE I am deeply comforted by my husband&rsquo;s understanding of what I&rsquo;m going through.
  NOTE I will need to be very careful of how much of my struggle I show to my young son.  Not so much that he is
burdened with adult worries, but enough so that he sees examples of struggle, persistance, and (grace under pressure)
  NOTE There is a lovely autumn mist over my home today. As I commute in to my beautiful chosen city, I am
reminded of how glad I am of my home and the choices I&rsquo;ve made.
  NOTE Take deep breaths.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Day of Ruby on Rails Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/07/first-day-of-ruby-on-rails-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-07T11:47:18-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/07/first-day-of-ruby-on-rails-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>First day of class</p>

<p>Kai is a very worried little boy.  He seems worried that Papa and I are going away for the next two months.  We tried to reassure him on the way to class, but there is so much we do not yet know about our schedule that I fear we didn&rsquo;t reassure him very well.  As we drove away, Papa and I commited to each other to give Kai some very focused time with each of us every evening.  I think it will be very important to focus on my family in the evenings.  This seems very in sync with CodeFellows, in that they emphasized not staying up late coding, but instead to prioritize getting enough sleep.  Good plan.</p>

<p>Only one other lady in the class.  Makes sense, since they alternate with a ladies only class, so most women probably attend that one.  I could see how intimidating this would be for many women.  It is awesome that they have the choice available.  I&rsquo;m used to this kind of percentage though, since I had the same ratios at university studying for my Computer Engineering (hardware) degree.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day Before Code Fellows Starts]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/06/day-before-code-fellows-starts/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-06T11:35:29-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/06/day-before-code-fellows-starts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Very nervious today.  CodeFellows starts tomorrow.  I&rsquo;m working out my nerves by thoroughly clearning several rooms in the house, knowing that this sort of thing will fall by the wayside for the next two months.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve got my laptop backed up, upgraded to OSX 10.8, and made sure everything still works.</p>

<p>My beloved boy is all sorts of worried and stressed by the changes we&rsquo;ve warned him are coming.</p>

<p>Time to get some good sleep before the adventure starts in the morning.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Ready for Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/09/16/getting-ready-for-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-16T21:56:47-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/09/16/getting-ready-for-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The news has finally come.  I have been accepted to both silver and gold.  I am excited, pleased, terrified, and eager.  I am torn
between wishing I&rsquo;d been qualified to skip silver and go straight to gold.  It would have been a nice time and money saver.  I am
also relieved, in that now I know I will be fully qualified as I start each class and won&rsquo;t be running to catch up a little as I
go straight into gold.  Additional huge bonus for me will be attending both bootcamps at the same time as my husband.  Sharing the
commute and sharing the experience together will be, I think, a great benefit for us both.</p>

<p>Now is the big push to try to get the blog launched before bootcamp starts in exactly 3 weeks.  This, on top of getting the ranch
ready for the rainy season, mostly this means spreading the contents of the compost bins on the pasture before the rain shuts down
that process for the season.  Additionally, I seem to have gotten it into my head to freeze and can fruits and sauces this year.
I&rsquo;ve been having fun experimenting with my new canning skills.  Thank you again to good friends who held a Jam Bee where an
experienced friend taught us how to make and can berry jam.  This gives me a nice way to store my husband&rsquo;s yummy spaghetti
sauce made with roma tomatoes from my garden.  I feel very domestic and accomplished.  I&rsquo;ll enjoy having the time for these
sorts of endeavors of love for my family while I am able.  Soon enough, I&rsquo;ll be taking care of my family using different talents.
It will be nice this winter, when I am thoroughly re-immersed in the working world, to be able to pull out some of those tasty
summer offerings tucked away on a shelf, brimming with flavors from the sun.  I never really thought of myself as the back to
nature, hippy type.  But I do love feeding my family so well with local produce.</p>

<p>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I GOT INTO CODE FELLOWS]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/09/12/i-got-into-code-fellows/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-12T21:54:16-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/09/12/i-got-into-code-fellows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Official Code Fellows Acceptance</p>

<p>I finally heard back from CodeFellows.  I&rsquo;m in!  Both Silver and Gold.</p>

<p>Yeay!</p>

<p>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Coding at the Festival]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/08/10/coding-at-the-festival/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-10T21:52:40-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/08/10/coding-at-the-festival</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It is a beautiful, partly cloudy afternoon at the Festival at Mt Si here in my little home town.  I am ensconced on a blanket on the grass, leaning against a large tree in a thoroughly shady spot.  There is a nice breeze.  The band playing nearby is a pleasant backdrop to the pleasant murmur of my neighbors and their children enjoying a lovely summer afternoon.</p>

<p>My free range son is running around, encountering friends, exhausting himself in the bouncy houses, and experiencing the thrill of a large climbing wall where a harness and helmet are required.  I feel pleasantly steeped in the community experience today.  I have chosen the right place to raise my family and spend the rest of my life.  The beauty of my surroundings is staggering.</p>

<p>And now, back to some more ruby coding.  I&rsquo;ve got to hurry up and finish that code for round two of the CodeFellows application.  I&rsquo;ve got a fun idea that has come together very well, so I am excited to get it ready for submission.</p>

<p>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preliminary Code Fellows Application Accepted]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/08/01/code-fellows-application-accepted/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-01T21:50:02-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/08/01/code-fellows-application-accepted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Code sample</h3>

<p>Code sample nearly complete.  I&rsquo;ve been checking into github all along the way.  It makes me feel a bit vulnerable to put the code out there while I&rsquo;m still working on it, but I will wait until I finish before I submit it officially.  Perhaps seeing how I put it together will give them more of a good impression that not.  I hope so.  I find myself being quite self conscious of my code.  My husband asked to take a look at it and has been pouring through it all afternoon&hellip;talk about self consciouness inducing.  Whew!</p>

<h3>Guessing my level</h3>

<p>I am very interested to see if I will qualify for the Silver or the Gold level of boot camp.  Gold means that I can skip the first month-long class and just take the second one.  It will be a lovely savings in time and money, so I am doing my best and we&rsquo;ll see how I rank.  The savings would be nice, but I am more interested in finding out where I place.  I find that sort of metric to be very interesting.  I&rsquo;m guessing that I rank about week 3 of 4 in the first month.  That would still mean that I need to take the first class too, but I&rsquo;ll have a very thorough review for the first week or so.  All to the good.  I could use a good portfolio of code snippets I&rsquo;ve written stored up on github for those code submissions that I&rsquo;ve been told companies are more interested in these days.</p>

<h3>Coding at the lake</h3>

<p>I had a lovely afternoon early this week having a picnic at Rattlesnake Lake with son, husband, and friend.  Perfect weather, not too hot, not too cold.  The others frolicked in the water, as I sat in the shade working out some snarls in my code.  Got all the code fixed that was broken.  Implemented additional code, some even worked right off.  All is unit tested.  Happy family.  Happy mama.</p>

<h3>Blueberries!</h3>

<p>Took another break yesterday morning to take son, husband, and friend blueberry picking at the local farm.  We came home with 16 pounds!  Reaped wonderful rewards at 2am while burning the midnight oil coding, as the smell of blueberry crumble wafted upstairs from the ambitious efforts of my brother&rsquo;s girlfriend.  Oh joy!  The merits of diligence to my work as well as taking time with my family.  I must be doing something right.</p>

<h3>Wrapup</h3>

<p>And now it is time to get back to figuring out that intro video.  I&rsquo;m taking a break from the code for the moment.  I&rsquo;ve done a lot over the last 24 hours, so I should give it a little bit of a rest before I leap in and implement that UI.</p>

<p>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Submitted Application to Code Fellows]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/07/26/submitted-application-to-code-fellows/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-26T21:48:26-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/07/26/submitted-application-to-code-fellows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I finally took a big and scary step.  I wrote and submitted my application to CodeFellows for the Ruby on Rails bootcamp this late fall.  I took my time and gave thoughtful responses and felt pretty good about it.  Less than an hour later, I already had a response.  On a Friday late afternoon!</p>

<p>I had made it to the next round of the Bootcamp Application.</p>

<p>Now, I just had to:</p>

<pre><code>1. Put together a short YouTube video introducing myself and explaining something technical related to programming.

2. Submit a best-foot-forward code sample.
</code></pre>

<p>I am elated to have made it to the next round.  I am also eager and nervous about the next requirements.  Oooo.  I think I
have a cool idea.  Off to see what I can work out.  Looks like the family will need to share me with technology this weekend.</p>

<p>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remembering Ruby]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/02/26/remembering-ruby/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-26T21:14:04-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/02/26/remembering-ruby</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Do I Want]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/02/01/what-do-i-want/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-01T20:19:07-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/02/01/what-do-i-want</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>An old friend from my old Santa Cruz days visited over Thanksgiving.  I was pretty uncomfortable in my own skin at the time and had been been feeling like I didn&rsquo;t have anyone I felt like I could turn to.  You see, I&rsquo;m a very strong personality.  Small surprise there, I know.  But what this ends up meaning is that for all I seem very strong and able on the outside, I have a lot of doubt and weakness on the inside.  I feel like so many people look up to me (I still am perplexed by this), that none of them feel to me like they are strong enough and have the perpective to be someone I can lean one and turn to when I&rsquo;m feeling week and in need of someone who sees me as just a person.  With faults and foibles, but loves me deeply and can give me that support that only a friend who has known you for many years can give you.  The kind of support that sometimes involves a boot in the arse.  Thank you, dear Kallie.</p>

<p>She reminded me of the things I find important.  And that my weakness was part of my strength and definitely part of my appeal.  She showed me the beginnings of the support that women can give one another.  And I started to discover some of the strength found from the support of other engineering women.  She reminded me, through many delightfully geeky conversations of my love for engineering, right down to the ones and zeros of circuit design.  To be sure I&rsquo;d learned the lesson, this valued friend sent me a LED clock engineering kit for my birthday in the beginning of 2013.  It wasn&rsquo;t very long before I took the time to start soldering the pieces of that clock.  So. Much. Fun.</p>

<p>Hey.  There it is.  My joy in engineering.  Still there, without a doubt.  OK, so now what&hellip;?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who Am I?]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2012/11/01/who-am-i/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-01T23:43:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2012/11/01/who-am-i</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<h2>  OUTLINE</h2>

<p>Title: &ldquo;Who are you?&rdquo; and &ldquo;What do you want?&rdquo;</p>

<ol>
<li><p>intro &ndash; name, handle</p></li>
<li><p>I am mare</p></li>
<li><p>I am mama</p></li>
<li><p>I am geeky</p></li>
<li><p>I am becoming a ruby on rails dev</p></li>
</ol>


<hr />

<h2> FIRST DRAFT</h2>

<p>&ldquo;Who are you?&rdquo; and &ldquo;What do you want?&rdquo;</p>

<p>Hello old friends.  Hello new friends.  Hello colleagues.  Hello young learners.  Hello respected professionals.  I am the GeekyMamaMare.  Welcome to my blog.  Please enjoy sharing my journey of re-discovering my passion in technology and re-directing (re-purposing?) my career from software testing to software development.  A wordy intro statement indeed, but very relevant to my journey as you will see in time.  Let&rsquo;s start by looking at who I am now.  The most important aspects of my life all fall into three categories.  My horses, my family, and my geekiness.  Everything I do in life ties into at least one of these.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been involved with horses my entire life.  They inspire me.  I love them deeply and their presence in my life is one of the foundations of my happiness and life satisfaction.  After hoping and planning from my early to mid-teens, I finally have my dream ranch and my horse breeding program.  I am working toward breeding honest, clever, and well-moving young horses that will, I hope, become that long sought after equine partner for the aspiring rider looking for just the right equine friend.  A challenging goal.  Intelligent horses can be a wonderful challenge to raise, but very rewarding as well.  My careful breeding choices are taking care of the intelligence and athleticism.  The daily focus of to raise and train up the youngsters in a loving but disciplined environment to produce and nurture their good and willing nature.</p>

<p>I am blessed with a wonderful family.  Most of all, by my son.  I am absolutely biased as any mother would be.  I find my son to be beautiful, very bright, energetic, loving and kind, gentle, a great adventuring partner, and a delight to watch learn and grow.  I am also incredibly lucky in that he seems to share my love of horses and things geeky.  I felt like I won the baby lottery when he was born back in 2009 and have felt that even more so as the years pass.  Certainly, he goes through the various challenges and foibles of every youngster, but I still feel like we have an easier time of it than most, and am very grateful to be so blessed.  I am also fortunate, especially in this journey of re-discovery, to have an understanding and supportive family.  It can be very difficult to change a career in midlife, especially with all the learning, studying, and growing that are involved in that process.  They were very worried about me as I realized I&rsquo;d lost my passion in technology.  And now they are encouraging, patient, and supportive as I learn and grow.  It can be very hard for the family at such a time.  I am so glad that they are behind me all the way.  I am very lucky.  I could be making these changes without their support.</p>

<p>In some ways, I was very sheltered while growing up in California&rsquo;s San Joaquin valley.  I had my horses, my books, a few friends, and a hugely active imagination.  I was mostly busy in my own world of pretend, but not too much so.  I was an adequate student without trying.  I was somewhat social as well as somewhat athletic.  I was also a voracious reader.  This last was probably what led me to declare myself &ldquo;weird&rdquo; in ninth grade.  I&rsquo;m not sure what I was going for at the time, but in hindsight, I was very right.  It was hard to be interested in elclectic, odd, and alternative things in the area where I grew up, since mainstream culture was almost all that was available.  But libraries were a good friend to me and my active imagination combined with new ideas and worlds and creatures from books allowed me to explore my &ldquo;weirdness&rdquo; or what I now call my geekiness.  As an adult, I moved to the San Francisco Bay Area and eventually to Santa Cruz where I found many other geeky people and interests to pursue.  I discovered Sci Fi/Fantasy conventions, the SCA, gaming, electronics, and so much more.  I worked hard at the local community college getting my core classes out of the way, then transferred to UC Santa Cruz, where I discovered that instead of majoring in programming, I could major in computer engineering, playing with chips, resistors, capacitors, and wiring, while taking programming classes as upper division electives.  So much fun!  I am still an electronics hobbiest and delight in pulling out my old soldering gun.</p>

<p>When just beginning my career with computers, there was a huge hiring freeze all through Silicon Valley.  This made finding a programming job very difficult for someone still in college.  I got an opportunity, but it started me on the path of software testing instead of programming.  I was initially a little unsatisfied, but eventually grew to love breaking software.  This satisfied me for a long while.  But eventually it was not enough.  I eventually landed my dream job in testing.  I was working with a product that I respected, with technology I enjoyed, with colleagues that were fun and challenging to work with, creating a product that was making a real difference in the world.  But it was a very small company.  And small companies must grow.  And when small companies grow, they change.  And often, those changes create a culture and a company mission that was not what it once was.  Parting with my dream job in the end was painful and made me quesion myself, my abilities, and my passion in technology entirely.  I spent that next year pursuing interests around my family and my horses in order to recover, since I was in no condition to market myself to a new company.  I eventually found my balance again, updated and polished up the ole resume, and dove into the job search.  I was ready to return to work.  I thought.  But as the weeks and then months passed, none of the job listings seemed right.  They were looking for skills I neither had nor wanted, or were working on things that held no interest.  I felt my passion for technology falling to the wayside, in the face of the drab, the mundane, the stultifying.  It was a low moment indeed.</p>

<p>Thus begins my journey.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
