<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Code Fellows | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/code-fellows/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-05T15:50:26-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Submitted Application to Code Fellows]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/10/submitted-application-to-code-fellows/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T20:48:26-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/10/submitted-application-to-code-fellows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>July 26th, 2013</p>

<p>Today I finally took a big and scary step.  I wrote and submitted my application to CodeFellows for the Ruby on Rails bootcamp this late fall.  I took my time and gave thoughtful responses and felt pretty good about it.  Less than an hour later, I already had a response.  On a Friday late afternoon!</p>

<p>I had made it to the next round of the Bootcamp Application.</p>

<p>Now, I just have to:</p>

<pre><code>1. Put together a short YouTube video introducing myself and explaining something technical related to programming.

2. Submit a best-foot-forward code sample.
</code></pre>

<p>I am elated to have made it to the next round.  I am also eager and nervous about the next requirements.  Oooo.  I think I
have a cool idea.  Off to see what I can work out.  Looks like the family will need to share me with technology this weekend.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Preliminary Code Fellows application accepted]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/05/code-fellows-application-accepted/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-05T20:50:02-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/05/code-fellows-application-accepted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>August 1st, 2013</p>

<h3>Code sample</h3>

<p>Code sample nearly complete.  I&rsquo;ve been checking into github all along the way.  It makes me feel a bit vulnerable to put the code out there while I&rsquo;m still working on it, but I will wait until I finish before I submit it officially.  Perhaps seeing how I put it together will give them more of a good impression that not.  I hope so.  I find myself being quite self conscious of my code.  My husband asked to take a look at it and has been pouring through it all afternoon&hellip;talk about self consciouness inducing.  Whew!</p>

<h3>Guessing my level</h3>

<p>I am very interested to see if I will qualify for the Silver or the Gold level of boot camp.  Gold means that I can skip the first month-long class and just take the second one.  It will be a lovely savings in time and money, so I am doing my best and we&rsquo;ll see how I rank.  The savings would be nice, but I am more interested in finding out where I place.  I find that sort of metric to be very interesting.  I&rsquo;m guessing that I rank about week 3 of 4 in the first month.  That would still mean that I need to take the first class too, but I&rsquo;ll have a very thorough review for the first week or so.  All to the good.  I could use a good portfolio of code snippets I&rsquo;ve written stored up on github for those code submissions that I&rsquo;ve been told companies are more interested in these days.</p>

<h3>Coding at the lake</h3>

<p>I had a lovely afternoon early this week having a picnic at Rattlesnake Lake with son, husband, and friend.  Perfect weather, not too hot, not too cold.  The others frolicked in the water, as I sat in the shade working out some snarls in my code.  Got all the code fixed that was broken.  Implemented additional code, some even worked right off.  All is unit tested.  Happy family.  Happy mama.</p>

<h3>Blueberries!</h3>

<p>Took another break yesterday morning to take son, husband, and friend blueberry picking at the local farm.  We came home with 16 pounds!  Reaped wonderful rewards at 2am while burning the midnight oil coding, as the smell of blueberry crumble wafted upstairs from the ambitious efforts of my brother&rsquo;s girlfriend.  Oh joy!  The merits of diligence to my work as well as taking time with my family.  I must be doing something right.</p>

<h3>Wrapup</h3>

<p>And now it is time to get back to figuring out that intro video.  I&rsquo;m taking a break from the code for the moment.  I&rsquo;ve done a lot over the last 24 hours, so I should give it a little bit of a rest before I leap in and implement that UI.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seattle Girl Geek Dinner - meet Code Fellows]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/20/seattle-girl-geek-dinner-meet-code-fellows/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-20T22:39:39-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/20/seattle-girl-geek-dinner-meet-code-fellows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>August 20th, 2013</p>

<p>8/20  Seattle Girl Geek Dinner, sponsored by Code Fellows</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code Fellows follow up application]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/15/code-fellows-follow-up-application/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-15T22:41:20-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/15/code-fellows-follow-up-application</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>timeline:9/8-9/9 CodeFellows follow up application (3 apps over 4 days, Yikes!!!)</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I GOT INTO CODE FELLOWS]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/10/i-got-into-code-fellows/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-10T20:54:16-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/10/i-got-into-code-fellows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>September 12th, 2013</p>

<p>Official Code Fellows Acceptance</p>

<p>I finally heard back from CodeFellows.  I&rsquo;m in!  Both Silver and Gold.</p>

<p>Yeay!</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
