<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: networking with women | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/networking-with-women/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-06T13:26:43-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Do I Want]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/20/what-do-i-want/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-20T21:19:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/20/what-do-i-want</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Thanksgiving visit</h3>

<p>An old friend from my old Santa Cruz days visited over Thanksgiving, 2012.  I was pretty uncomfortable in my own skin at the time and had been been feeling like I didn&rsquo;t have anyone I felt like I could turn to.</p>

<h3>Turning to others is hard</h3>

<p>You see, I&rsquo;m a very strong personality.  Small surprise there, I know.  But what this ends up meaning is that for all I seem very strong and able on the outside, I have a lot of doubt and weakness on the inside.  I feel like so many people look up to me (I still am perplexed by this), but none of them feel to me like they are strong enough and have the perpective to be someone I can lean one and turn to when I&rsquo;m feeling week and in need of someone who sees me as just a person.  Sees me with my faults and foibles, but loves me deeply and so can give me that support that only a friend who has known you for many years can give you.  The kind of support that sometimes involves a boot in the arse.  Thank you, dear Kallie.</p>

<h3>Rediscovering my geekery</h3>

<p>She reminded me of the things I find important.  And that my weakness was part of my strength and definitely part of my appeal.  She showed me the beginnings of the support that women can give one another.  And I started to discover some of the strength found from the support of other engineering women.  She reminded me, through many delightfully geeky conversations of my love for engineering, right down to the ones and zeros of circuit design.  To be sure I&rsquo;d learned the lesson, this valued friend sent me a LED clock engineering kit for my birthday in the beginning of 2013.  It wasn&rsquo;t very long before I took the time to start soldering the pieces of that clock.  So. Much. Fun.</p>

<p>Hey.  There it is.  My joy in engineering.  Still there, without a doubt.</p>

<p>OK, so now what&hellip;?</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Networking with women in STEM]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/05/networking-with-women-in-stem/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-05T22:57:51-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/05/networking-with-women-in-stem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>March 28-31st, 2013</p>

<h3>NorWesCon panels and coding</h3>

<p>Spring brought with it the local literary convention, NorWesCon.  There were several panels that got me thinking about women in STEM (science, technology, engineering, math), networking within my industry, and how to re-find my passion in technology.  I decided it was time to pick back up my long abandoned pursuit of programming and to start networking with other women in technology for mutual support and growth.</p>

<h3>Networking with women</h3>

<p>Most of my social connections previously have been with men, so networking with women is a frightening notion for me.  I have long shied away from Ladies Nights Out as being very foreign and uncomfortable and not very applicable.  But, I needed to get out more and freshen my networking skills as a preparation for interviewing so I time to plunge forward right outside my comfort zone.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GeekGirlCon networking meetup]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/25/geekgirlcon-networking-meetup/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-25T23:00:35-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/25/geekgirlcon-networking-meetup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>April 11th, 2013</p>

<h3>GeekGirlCon Cocktail Connections</h3>

<p>This was the first in my networking event line up.  A meetup for the purpose of networking with other geeky women.  It seemed like a good first step to get me started on networking.  I was very nervous going into this, since this sort of thing is way outside of my comfort zone.  Ok, deep breath, I can do this.</p>

<h3>Not so bad</h3>

<p>It turned out that these are good and friendly folk.  We were all mostly new, but that helped somewhat.  I introduced myself to a number of folks and worked on those introduction sorts of conversations.  Some were more successful that others.  I&rsquo;m glad I went.  This was a good training event in how to network.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[She's Geeky]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/10/shes-geeky/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-10T23:28:23-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/10/shes-geeky</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>April 26th &amp; 27th, 2013</p>

<p>I joined several relevent local meetup groups and then I learned of She&rsquo;s Geeky 13, Seattle.  This is an un-conference for women geeks of all kinds to share, connect, network, learn, inspire, and enjoy (paraphrased from the She&rsquo;s Geeky website, shesgeeky.org).</p>

<p>I enjoyed panels on public speaking, mentoring, Ruby and online learning, and very importantly for me: Impostor Syndrome.  Oh that last one was an eye opener for me to be sure.  It explains a lot to me about why so many women in technology have a hard time putting themselves forward unless or until they are very sure of themselves.  It is very reassuring to me to know how many suffer from this and not all of them women either.</p>

<p>Attending this un-conference made all the difference in the world and confirmed the wisdom of my ideas.  I finalized my plan for re-purposing my career with the attendant studying, learning, networking needed over the next several months to change my career from being a 20 year software tester, to being a newby Ruby on Rails developer.</p>

<p>I came out of this experience realizing that I was on an amazing journey.  I also realized the importance of sharing my travels so that other people, particularly women, could see a path that could be taken, and that great change can be made by normal people.  Thanks to some encouragement I received during She&rsquo;s Geeky I saw the wisdom of writing about my experience, thus I first put &ldquo;pen&rdquo; to this blog of my journey on May 8, 2013.</p>

<p>Thank you, She&rsquo;s Geeky, for the inspiration, the encouragement, and the courage to give it all a try.  I can&rsquo;t wait until next time!</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Codechix Ruby on Rails hacking session]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/25/codechix-ruby-on-rails-hacking-session/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-25T22:33:05-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/25/codechix-ruby-on-rails-hacking-session</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>July 14th, 2013</p>

<p>7/14  First ruby/rails ladies meetup (thanks to codechix and Shaili Guru)</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
