<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: meetups | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/meetups/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-06T21:34:58-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Networking with women in STEM]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/05/networking-with-women-in-stem/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-05T22:57:51-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/05/networking-with-women-in-stem</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>March 28-31st, 2013</p>

<h3>NorWesCon panels and coding</h3>

<p>Spring brought with it the local literary convention, NorWesCon.  There were several panels that got me thinking about women in STEM (science, technology, engineering, math), networking within my industry, and how to re-find my passion in technology.  I decided it was time to pick back up my long abandoned pursuit of programming and to start networking with other women in technology for mutual support and growth.</p>

<h3>Networking with women</h3>

<p>Most of my social connections previously have been with men, so networking with women is a frightening notion for me.  I have long shied away from Ladies Nights Out as being very foreign and uncomfortable and not very applicable.  But, I needed to get out more and freshen my networking skills as a preparation for interviewing so I time to plunge forward right outside my comfort zone.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[GeekGirlCon networking meetup]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/25/geekgirlcon-networking-meetup/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-25T23:00:35-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/25/geekgirlcon-networking-meetup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>April 11th, 2013</p>

<h3>GeekGirlCon Cocktail Connections</h3>

<p>This was the first in my networking event line up.  A meetup for the purpose of networking with other geeky women.  It seemed like a good first step to get me started on networking.  I was very nervous going into this, since this sort of thing is way outside of my comfort zone.  Ok, deep breath, I can do this.</p>

<h3>Not so bad</h3>

<p>It turned out that these are good and friendly folk.  We were all mostly new, but that helped somewhat.  I introduced myself to a number of folks and worked on those introduction sorts of conversations.  Some were more successful that others.  I&rsquo;m glad I went.  This was a good training event in how to network.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Seattle Rails Educational/Networking Meetup]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/15/seattle-rails-educational-slash-networking-meetup/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-15T23:04:01-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/03/15/seattle-rails-educational-slash-networking-meetup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>April 16th, 2013</p>

<h3>Seattle Rails community</h3>

<p>The Seattle Rails educational and networking meetup was an evening-long event with two technical talks, dinner, and networking.  I was pretty nervous going into this, since my programming skills are rusty at best, and I am completely new to Ruby.</p>

<h3>MINSWAN</h3>

<p>The Rails community, however, was very welcoming.  I felt encouraged and came away eager to continue forward learning Ruby and Rails as well as networking with folks in that community.  &ldquo;Matz is nice, so we are nice.&rdquo;  This is a phrase I learned at this event referring to the ruby language designer,  Mr. Yukihiro Matsumoto (Matz).</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
