<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: vacation | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/vacation/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-09T19:40:39-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Family summer vacation]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/20/family-summer-vacation/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-20T22:37:45-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/20/family-summer-vacation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>July 17-21, 2013</p>

<p>Something I haven&rsquo;t been mentioning too much yet is the importance of taking time for yourself and for your family.  It can be a lot of effort in logistics and preparation, but going away with my family and putting most of our every day responsibilities aside for a time can be a wonderful way to relax and reconnect.</p>

<p>Some of the family is involved in a martial art.  The art has a summer camp every year that is an extended weekend campout at a beautiful lake on the Olympic peninsula.  The participants organize into little workshops or hikes on the days leading up to the last day when all gather for the summer Belt Test.</p>

<p>I am fortunate that this is an event that is looked forward to by the whole family.  We keep it pretty civilized though by staying in an RV.  We like our hot showers and easy cooking facilities, not to mention the espresso machine and power for our devices.  I mean really, how would I blog without power?  Still, much of the time is spent together around the campfire, swimming, hiking, or playing games.</p>

<p>The weather was lovely.  The company was good.  Swimming in the lake was divine.  Our little boy had such a good time, with a possible exception of one late night when his tummy decided ENOUGH!.  Ah well, I managed to get Everything cleaned up in the Rented RV after only 2 or 3 hours.  Poor little guy.  Poor mama.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
