<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: passion | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/passion/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-06T13:26:43-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How my journey begins]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/27/how-my-journey-begins/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-27T22:49:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/27/how-my-journey-begins</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>My introduction</h3>

<p>Hello old friends.  Hello new friends.  Hello colleagues.  Hello young learners.  Hello respected professionals.  I am the GeekyMamaMare.  Welcome to my blog.  Please enjoy sharing my journey of re-discovering my passion in technology and re-directing (re-purposing?) my career from software testing to software development.  A wordy intro statement indeed, but very relevant to my journey as you will see in time.  Let&rsquo;s start by looking at the dilemna I found myself in.</p>

<h3>Broken heart</h3>

<p>I had been a quality engineer in the computer industry for 20 years, when, in the summer of 2011, my dream job fell through my hands.  I was devastated.  I quickly realized that I was far too emotionally fragile for the moment and needed to take some time away from the industry to recover from my heart ache.</p>

<h3>Where&rsquo;s the passion?</h3>

<p>A year passed and I refreshed my resume and leapt back into the job seeking pool.  I have been fortunate in the past that each job came along just as it was needed, usually through networking, and generally right along the lines of where I wanted my career to go.  This time was a different experience.  None of the jobs available seemed to be a good fit for my skills or my experience.  I also was beginning to discover a lack of motivation in my search.  It was as if my passion for technology and computers was missing.</p>

<h3>Identifying my priorities</h3>

<p>I took a bit of time to figure out my priorities and what made me eager to go to work in the morning, only to discover that I really wasn&rsquo;t seeing anything available in the job market that made me eager to leave my family, my son, my ranch, and my horses in the morning.</p>

<p>My new goals started to come clear.</p>

<h3>My goal</h3>

<p>I wanted to renew my passion for technology such that I could find a company to contribute to that made me as eager to head to the office in the morning as I was to return to my beloved ranch in the evening.</p>

<p>Ok, good goal.  Now to develop a plan to take me towards that goal.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Do I Want]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/20/what-do-i-want/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-20T21:19:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/20/what-do-i-want</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Thanksgiving visit</h3>

<p>An old friend from my old Santa Cruz days visited over Thanksgiving, 2012.  I was pretty uncomfortable in my own skin at the time and had been been feeling like I didn&rsquo;t have anyone I felt like I could turn to.</p>

<h3>Turning to others is hard</h3>

<p>You see, I&rsquo;m a very strong personality.  Small surprise there, I know.  But what this ends up meaning is that for all I seem very strong and able on the outside, I have a lot of doubt and weakness on the inside.  I feel like so many people look up to me (I still am perplexed by this), but none of them feel to me like they are strong enough and have the perpective to be someone I can lean one and turn to when I&rsquo;m feeling week and in need of someone who sees me as just a person.  Sees me with my faults and foibles, but loves me deeply and so can give me that support that only a friend who has known you for many years can give you.  The kind of support that sometimes involves a boot in the arse.  Thank you, dear Kallie.</p>

<h3>Rediscovering my geekery</h3>

<p>She reminded me of the things I find important.  And that my weakness was part of my strength and definitely part of my appeal.  She showed me the beginnings of the support that women can give one another.  And I started to discover some of the strength found from the support of other engineering women.  She reminded me, through many delightfully geeky conversations of my love for engineering, right down to the ones and zeros of circuit design.  To be sure I&rsquo;d learned the lesson, this valued friend sent me a LED clock engineering kit for my birthday in the beginning of 2013.  It wasn&rsquo;t very long before I took the time to start soldering the pieces of that clock.  So. Much. Fun.</p>

<p>Hey.  There it is.  My joy in engineering.  Still there, without a doubt.</p>

<p>OK, so now what&hellip;?</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
