<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: pain | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/pain/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-06T23:09:49-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How my journey begins]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/27/how-my-journey-begins/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-27T22:49:04-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/27/how-my-journey-begins</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>My introduction</h3>

<p>Hello old friends.  Hello new friends.  Hello colleagues.  Hello young learners.  Hello respected professionals.  I am the GeekyMamaMare.  Welcome to my blog.  Please enjoy sharing my journey of re-discovering my passion in technology and re-directing (re-purposing?) my career from software testing to software development.  A wordy intro statement indeed, but very relevant to my journey as you will see in time.  Let&rsquo;s start by looking at the dilemna I found myself in.</p>

<h3>Broken heart</h3>

<p>I had been a quality engineer in the computer industry for 20 years, when, in the summer of 2011, my dream job fell through my hands.  I was devastated.  I quickly realized that I was far too emotionally fragile for the moment and needed to take some time away from the industry to recover from my heart ache.</p>

<h3>Where&rsquo;s the passion?</h3>

<p>A year passed and I refreshed my resume and leapt back into the job seeking pool.  I have been fortunate in the past that each job came along just as it was needed, usually through networking, and generally right along the lines of where I wanted my career to go.  This time was a different experience.  None of the jobs available seemed to be a good fit for my skills or my experience.  I also was beginning to discover a lack of motivation in my search.  It was as if my passion for technology and computers was missing.</p>

<h3>Identifying my priorities</h3>

<p>I took a bit of time to figure out my priorities and what made me eager to go to work in the morning, only to discover that I really wasn&rsquo;t seeing anything available in the job market that made me eager to leave my family, my son, my ranch, and my horses in the morning.</p>

<p>My new goals started to come clear.</p>

<h3>My goal</h3>

<p>I wanted to renew my passion for technology such that I could find a company to contribute to that made me as eager to head to the office in the morning as I was to return to my beloved ranch in the evening.</p>

<p>Ok, good goal.  Now to develop a plan to take me towards that goal.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
