<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: bootcamp | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/bootcamp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-28T00:58:56-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Successfully graduated Code Fellows]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/04/successfully-graduated-code-fellows/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-04T22:44:03-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/04/successfully-graduated-code-fellows</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>12/4  Graduated CodeFellows</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 23 of Code Fellows Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/11/06/day-23-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-06T13:55:15-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/11/06/day-23-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wednesday the 6th of November, 2013  8:02 am</p>

<p>  So, late last week, one of our instructors was commenting about how one of
the founders of seattle.rb, Ryan Davis, had been bugging him to make
attending the next seattle.rb meetup and presenting either a lightning talk
or our class projects a required assignment for everyone in class. Thank you,
Ryan. /sarcasm
  Well, Ivan kindly did not make this mandatory, yet, seeing the wisdom, in
spite of my fears (and I assure you, they were plenty), my partner and I
presented our class project  So the next day, I got on to the seattle.rb site
and signed us up  The attendance was enourmous, apparently about three times
their norm. But that&rsquo;s what you get when you nag CodeFellows and the Ada
Academy to attend; well, there&rsquo;s a lot of us.
  It was absolutely delightful to meet the women from the Ada Academy. The
Ada Academy is a year-long program for women who want to be developers but
have little to absolutely no experience in most cases. I got to bring out
several of my pet hobbyhorses, much to their entertainment; impostor syndrome,
the hard work and hard won skill that is networking (meaning going to these
meetings and interacting with <em>gasp</em> humans. New ones! That you don&rsquo;t already
know!). It was flattering to realize that listening in the background was
Carrie Miller, one of the founders/teachers/somethingorother of the Ada
Academy. Carrie is a strong leader for women in technology. Her name and face
keep coming across my screen, usually through devchicks, but other places,
too, where good conversations are happening about the challenges women face
in technology, particularly the computer industry. It was a pleasure to later
meet her and speak with her further about the Ada Academy.
  The presentation went well.  The Adas in particular were a very appriciative
audience and took the time later to say how much they enjoyed it.  I went home
exhausted, it being several hours after my usual bedtime, but feeling strong
in the path I&rsquo;ve chosen and where it&rsquo;s taking me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 20, last day of Silver. I made it to GOLD!]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/11/01/i-made-it-to-gold/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-01T15:48:17-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/11/01/i-made-it-to-gold</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  Oh.  Em.  Gee.
  We made it.
  Listening around the work tables at CodeFellows this week, as we were all
working on our class projects, I started hearing other people saying little
things that suggested to me that I was not the only one scared, behind, and
terrified that I was not going to pass Silver. They did not say it in so many
words, but I heard a lot of worry. Of course, what I saw when I looked at
their screens was a level of polish that made made my knees quake with, yeah,
you guessed it, Impostor Syndrome. But the words I was hearing, the furrowed
brows I was seeing, the increasingly frazzled appearances, suggested to me
that these, my peers, might be in the same boat I was.
  Today was the day. One PM was code freeze. Ivan sounded the gong at
exactly one, over and over, and shooed us all downstairs to present Our
Projects. I made sure, over the last two days, to keep an eye on the look
and feel of our project, knowing that just functionality is important, too,
but dropping design on the floor would be a mistake. I came into today very
nervous, but a little bit hopeful, because I was proud of our little site. It
looked good. It made me feel good to look at it. And that helped, giving me
just that tiniest bit of courage with which I stepped forward and presented&hellip;
first. <em>cue dramatic music</em> The presentation went well. I felt good and
confidant about what I was speaking of. My partner was the same. I had enough
to show off that I didn&rsquo;t even cover everything. I talked knowledgely about
the design decisions we made. And humourously about points of pain, confusion,
and trouble. And my audience seemed engaged and interested. I finished up
feeling&hellip; pleased. And excited. And exhausted. The other presentations of my
fellows seemed comperable in areas of strength, areas of weakness, areas of
pain, and areas of joyful technological discovery. All different, as different
people think differently and have different interests. But my fellow
bootcampers finally felt like peers. We had suffered together and we had all,
to a one, emerged triumphant.
  There was a social afterwards. With the usual libations, offered as we
shuffled desks around, since another class had just completed and a new one
had just started. The comaradarie and exhuberant energy, as well as the
occasional flat affect of mental and physical exhaustion abounded. I felt an
equal with these twenty other people at last. Even as recently as yesterday,
I would not quite have felt comfortable tapping any one of them for technical
help. Now, I feel like I could speak up at a tablefull and say &lsquo;Hey, does
anyone know how to help with this?&rsquo; Not the sort of thing I do easily. So this
is a big point of growth for me. And a warm relief.
  I still feel like I could take a month between silver and gold to finish and
wrap up all the learnings and projects and code samples that I want to write.
And I will, but it looks like it will be <em>after</em> gold.
  YAY I MADE IT TO GOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOOLD.
  And now, as I commute home, in the autumn dusk, I bask in the beauty of the
random patterns of the clouds, the soft colors of the sunset, framing the
beautiful spectacle of Mount Rainer, and enjoy this moment of triumph and
peace before I leap into it all again on Monday.
  And now I go home to spend a lovely weekend with son, family, ranch, and
sleep.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 19 of Code Fellows Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/31/day-19-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-31T14:08:54-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/31/day-19-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> <em>said in a measuredly quiet voice</em>
  don&rsquo;t.  panic.
  I feel like I&rsquo;m so far behind that the natural human tendancy makes me want
to panic. It makes me want to panic, makes me want to dither, makes me want
to run screaming off into the night.
  I can&rsquo;t do that. It is too important that I stay the course, that I stay on
task.
  (yay carpools)
  I&rsquo;ve thought of some additional resources at my fingertips, and I&rsquo;m going to
start using those more, as well. And the important thing is that I don&rsquo;t let
that gibbering thing inside me take over.  Instead, I need to see what I&rsquo;ve
done, identify the piece I don&rsquo;t understand, wrap it up and put it aside, and
move on to the next thing. I need to stare at the screen reading documentation
less; it&rsquo;s not getting me very far. A little of it, certainly, but after the
third reading, I should start questioning. Code School&rsquo;s Rails for Zombies and
the RailCasts have a lot of good resoures. Taking a half or even an hour out
to learn more through one of those means won&rsquo;t take a lot away from what I&rsquo;m
accomplishing and can instead help me go forward by leaps and bounds. If I&rsquo;d
only pursued that a bit sooner, I&rsquo;d be a lot further along. Ah well, the
perfection of hindsight.</p>

<p>  I learned long ago to just keep putting one foot in front of the other, so
 that, at least, if you do fall, you&rsquo;ll fall in the correct direction. And
 that&rsquo;s making progress, too, right?</p>

<p> I&rsquo;m at the point where I&rsquo;m thinking code almost every minute of the day. I
chew on it in my dreams, I wake up wanting to sit down at my computer and
work on this or that. And I go to bed early with my son exausted and wishing
I had more resources. The whole family is showing signs of the draining
fatigue from this amazing experience. The price is very high for all of us,
but we are all committed and pulling together for the benefits to us all will
be enduring and worth it. And to be honest, the day-by-day experience is worth
it.  Exhausting as hell, but worth it.  And I remember that, most of the time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 13 of Code Fellows Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/23/day-13-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-23T13:50:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/10/23/day-13-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  I sacrifices sleeping in last night.  Well, not last night, but this
morning.  That&rsquo;s my story and I&rsquo;m sticking to it.
  I&rsquo;m still feeling dreadfully behind, which is to say I&rsquo;m still one week
behind.  Just like last week, when I was&hellip; one week behind.  Which means I&rsquo;m
not falling futher behind. There&rsquo;s some merit there. There are fewer and
fewer questions coming up in class lecture. The questions also seem
entirely based around the most current material. During my early morning
midnght oil burning, I came to the suspicion that far more of my classmates
are just as thoroughly behind and are feeling just as awkward about asking
questions as a result. Mostly I don&rsquo;t have a question for my instructors
because as I am progressing, I no sooner come up with a question than I
shortly discover the answer and move on to the next bit of learning.  Repeat,
slowly, a lot. I feel pretty good about the things I&rsquo;m learning, but then
the instructors asks one of those questions in class. One of those perfect
interview questions.  Something very fundamental to the understanding to
the understanding of Ruby or Rails or object-oriented programming, and I
watch the entire class flail helplessly, along with myself, as we struggle
for the words or concepts and a means to express them.
  They told us early on that they did not select us for the class because of
how smart we were.  We were chosen for this class because of how hard we work
and how hard we try. OH BOY do I hope that&rsquo;s true.  If it is, then I will make
it through.  Somehow.  One step at a time.  If not, well, I was doomed from
the outset.  So, no need to stress, just need to do.  And do.  And do.
  And maybe catch up on a little sleep this weekend.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
