<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: bootcamp | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/bootcamp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-05T15:50:26-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Day of Ruby on Rails Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/20/first-day-of-ruby-on-rails-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-20T10:47:18-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/20/first-day-of-ruby-on-rails-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>October 7th, 2013</p>

<p>First day of class</p>

<p>Kai is a very worried little boy.  He seems worried that Papa and I are going away for the next two months.  We tried to reassure him on the way to class, but there is so much we do not yet know about our schedule that I fear we didn&rsquo;t reassure him very well.  As we drove away, Papa and I commited to each other to give Kai some very focused time with each of us every evening.  I think it will be very important to focus on my family in the evenings.  This seems very in sync with CodeFellows, in that they emphasized not staying up late coding, but instead to prioritize getting enough sleep.  Good plan.</p>

<p>Only one other lady in the class.  Makes sense, since they alternate with a ladies only class, so most women probably attend that one.  I could see how intimidating this would be for many women.  It is awesome that they have the choice available.  I&rsquo;m used to this kind of percentage though, since I had the same ratios at university studying for my Computer Engineering (hardware) degree.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 3 of Code Fellows bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/15/day-3-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-15T07:59:42-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/15/day-3-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>8 am, October 9th, 2013</p>

<p>They told us the first day not to stay up late doing our work. Get up early, sure, but don&rsquo;t stay up late. It was Day 2 of bootcamp, and I already felt like I was struggling with the load. I stayed up until 1 am, I got it all done, and then I started Day 3 four hours later.</p>

<p>In those early morning hours today at home, I broke down and lost it. I&rsquo;m scared that I&rsquo;m going to struggle and try and not be able to learn enough, quickly enough, to get through bootcamp. CodeFellows is a fellowship of professionals and I&rsquo;m scared that they&rsquo;re going to take away my t-shirt. And what I mean by that is if I am struggling so much after only two days, how can it be that I belong in this class of amazing learners.</p>

<p>And so I will document this struggle and I will share my pain with you.</p>

<p>Because, dammit, if I can get through this and succeed you can, too.</p>

<p>Now if I can just hold it together long enough to get through Day 3 of class.  One day at a time.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>


<p>NOTE Meticulous attention to detail may be setting me up to lose.</p>

<p>NOTE I am deeply comforted by my husband&rsquo;s understanding of what I&rsquo;m going through.</p>

<p>NOTE I will need to be very careful of how much of my struggle I show to my young son.  Not so much that he is burdened with adult worries, but enough so that he sees examples of struggle, persistance, and (grace under pressure)</p>

<p>NOTE There is a lovely autumn mist over my home today. As I commute in to my beautiful chosen city, I am reminded of how glad I am of my home and the choices I&rsquo;ve made.</p>

<p>NOTE Take deep breaths.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 4 of Code Fellows bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/10/day-4-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-10T18:47:42-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/10/day-4-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>October 10th, 2013</p>

<p>In the middle of the afternoon lab, fighting with things that are not working.  I have experienced one of the typical problems for women in STEM.  We are simply not heard.  9 students all working with an instructor, trying to work together to get us all through a difficult issue.  Two of my male classmates are starting to have success.  I ask them questions several times.  I say their names.  But not once do they look up or hear me.  Note, they are the two people closest to me.  One is RIGHT next to me.  One is in front of me.</p>

<p>I finally give up on the entire experience entirely.  I sit up straight, eyes forward, smiling slightly, hands folded on the table.  You know the position.  It is the one we are taught when we first start school.  The one that all the girls do and all the boys blow off.  After several more minutes of being ignored, which I expected really since I was mostly trying to regain my composure, I finally lose it and step away to sob my heart out in the bathroom.  I finally (sorta) put myself together and head back.  I see the two men leave the room in triumph, having succeeded where the rest of us are still struggling.</p>

<p>I sit back down.  Still unable to get anywhere, nor do I have the concentration to try at this point.  I start this post to get down this feeling.  And have just run back to the bathroom, unable to hold it together any more.  My face is now beet red and my eyes are puffy.</p>

<p>Why are women not even heard!?</p>

<p>Two women in a class of 21.  I understand very well why they have a women only bootcamp.  How I wish I took that one instead.  I fear dearly that this was all a very expensive mistake.  I want to never ask technical help from ANY man ever again.  Why should I bother.  I&rsquo;ll just be dismisse anyway.  It happened just last night with my own (male) housemates, so why should I expect any better treatment than I get at home.  And my housemates are self proclaimed feminists!</p>

<p>Ok, cleaning up to go try again.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 8 of Code Fellows Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/05/day-8-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-05T11:10:08-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/05/day-8-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wednesday, October 16, 2013</p>

<p>It still feels ilke drinking from the firehose, and I still feel like in
some ways I&rsquo;m way behind. But what I am learning is amazing. I am learning so many things, so many tools, so many ways of thinking and I am absolutely loving it. I&rsquo;ve been in industry, what I am learning is incredibly relevant to what you do and what you use EVERY day.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve recovered my strength. Sleep is important! So is good And frequent
Nutrition.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m still behind and don&rsquo;t know how I&rsquo;m going to catch up, but in some ways, I&rsquo;m right with the class or even at the forefront in some of the work, so I am encouraged.</p>

<p>I would absolutely do this again, and very much believe that I am on the
right path. I think about what I used to do in my job and it still shuts me down inside, and now I think about what I&rsquo;m doing with a smile on my face and a spring in my step, even at home, staring off in the distance, musing about some little change I want to make in my portfolio.  This is the passion I want I see in my day to day career, and I could not be more pleased that it is back.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day 12 of Code Fellows Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/11/30/day-12-of-code-fellows-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-30T16:03:22-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/11/30/day-12-of-code-fellows-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>October 22nd, 2013</p>

<p>Still behind, but finding my rhythm.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m starting to find my balance with both the work and trying to keep up
with the basic things, you know, like eating, sleeping, clean clothes, that sort of thing. All my spare time, and there isn&rsquo;t much, is for my family and my little boy. We all seem to be doing all right, but I think he&rsquo;s paying the highest price. It is hard for a child to, when they have enjoyed the luxury of their parents home for nearly their first five years of life, now have ALL of that change. To have mama working, to have papa working, to have uncle working, and only one at home supporting the rest of us.</p>

<p>In class, I feel like I&rsquo;m always behind, but I still feel like I&rsquo;m learning very effective, and getting everything implemented successfully, but the going, while thorough, is still slow.</p>

<p>The good news is that the class project, where I&rsquo;m collaborating with
someone else, is something my husband and I have been wanting to do for a
very long time.  It&rsquo;s an idea that has been developing for a couple of years now, and it ends up being so well tailored for this class as a demonstration of our skills that I am a bit startled in just how appropriate it is. This also means YAY! something to be ahead on, and we are. If we can keep up that pattern, I think we may be able to catch up on everything.</p>

<p>The class is still, as we like to call it at home, &lsquo;drinking from the
informational firehose&rsquo;. And it is hard not to choke. It is important to keep panic at bay with good eating habits, lots of sleep, and stopping to take a breath now and then.  To that end, this last weekend, I took my family to GeekGirlCon. But husband and I spent as much time as we could with our noses in our laptops. The environment was both distracting and encouraging. I got to share with several people what CodeFellows was, since my costume was the same professional wardrobe that I wear every day to class with my CodeFellows t-shirt under my dress coat.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been to a number of conventions. Mostly science fiction, ComicCon,
WorldCon, only one or two professional conventions.  And this con was
unique. I have never felt so welcomed and so encouraged by every person I
met. I have also never seen that many women all getting their geek on.
Teaching.  Learning.  Encouraging.  Enthusing.  And all of them happy to
share. I have always undervalued the power of women working together and
supporting one another. Part of this journey is learning is learning how
important that is. And why I want to seek it out.  For myself and to nurture it in others. I will not be missing another GeekGirlCon, and it is only in its third year.  What an amazing force for good this convention is and will be. I can only imagine that this convention is for geekdom what the Grace Hopper Conference is for STEM.  I hope next year to attend Grace Hopper to find out for myself.</p>

<p>Blog Notes: I tried to take the time during my commute daily to simply admire autumn&rsquo;s beauty dripping its colors through the trees. The mists drift over the waterways, sometimes shrouding my valley in white. And then a spear of sunlight pierces the mists, striking in its contrast.s</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
