<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: preparations | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/preparations/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-28T00:31:11-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Ready for Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/05/getting-ready-for-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-05T20:56:47-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/01/05/getting-ready-for-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The news has finally come.  I have been accepted to both silver and gold.  I am excited, pleased, terrified, and eager.  I am torn
between wishing I&rsquo;d been qualified to skip silver and go straight to gold.  It would have been a nice time and money saver.  I am
also relieved, in that now I know I will be fully qualified as I start each class and won&rsquo;t be running to catch up a little as I
go straight into gold.  Additional huge bonus for me will be attending both bootcamps at the same time as my husband.  Sharing the
commute and sharing the experience together will be, I think, a great benefit for us both.</p>

<p>Now is the big push to try to get the blog launched before bootcamp starts in exactly 3 weeks.  This, on top of getting the ranch
ready for the rainy season, mostly this means spreading the contents of the compost bins on the pasture before the rain shuts down
that process for the season.  Additionally, I seem to have gotten it into my head to freeze and can fruits and sauces this year.
I&rsquo;ve been having fun experimenting with my new canning skills.  Thank you again to good friends who held a Jam Bee where an
experienced friend taught us how to make and can berry jam.  This gives me a nice way to store my husband&rsquo;s yummy spaghetti
sauce made with roma tomatoes from my garden.  I feel very domestic and accomplished.  I&rsquo;ll enjoy having the time for these
sorts of endeavors of love for my family while I am able.  Soon enough, I&rsquo;ll be taking care of my family using different talents.
It will be nice this winter, when I am thoroughly re-immersed in the working world, to be able to pull out some of those tasty
summer offerings tucked away on a shelf, brimming with flavors from the sun.  I never really thought of myself as the back to
nature, hippy type.  But I do love feeding my family so well with local produce.</p>

<p>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
