<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: family | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/family/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-06T21:34:58-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Who Am I]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/25/who-am-i/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-25T23:43:52-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/25/who-am-i</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>To make a goal, I find it important to know who you are, why you are that way, and what is important to you.</p>

<p>The most important aspects of my life all fall into three categories.  My horses, my family, and my geekiness.  Everything I do in life ties into at least one of these.  That is the TL;DR version.  To learn more about me and what I find most important, read on.</p>

<h3>Horses</h3>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been involved with horses my entire life.  They inspire me.  I love them deeply and their presence in my life is one of the foundations of my happiness and life satisfaction.  After hoping and planning from my early to mid-teens, I finally have my dream ranch and my horse breeding program.  I am working toward breeding honest, clever, and well-moving young horses that will, I hope, become that long sought after equine partner for the aspiring rider looking for just the right equine friend.  A challenging goal.  Intelligent horses can be a wonderful challenge to raise, but very rewarding as well.  My careful breeding choices are taking care of the intelligence and athleticism.  The daily focus of to raise and train up the youngsters in a loving but disciplined environment to produce and nurture their good and willing nature.</p>

<h3>Family</h3>

<p>I am blessed with a wonderful family.  Most of all, by my son.  I am absolutely biased as any mother would be.  I find my son to be beautiful, very bright, energetic, loving and kind, gentle, a great adventuring partner, and a delight to watch learn and grow.  I am also incredibly lucky in that he seems to share my love of horses and things geeky.  I felt like I won the baby lottery when he was born back in 2009 and have felt that even more so as the years pass.  Certainly, he goes through the various challenges and foibles of every youngster, but I still feel like we have an easier time of it than most, and am very grateful to be so blessed.  I am also fortunate, especially in this journey of re-discovery, to have an understanding and supportive family.  It can be very difficult to change a career in midlife, especially with all the learning, studying, and growing that are involved in that process.  They were very worried about me as I realized I&rsquo;d lost my passion in technology.  And now they are encouraging, patient, and supportive as I learn and grow.  It can be very hard for the family at such a time.  I am so glad that they are behind me all the way.  I am very lucky.  I could be making these changes without their support.</p>

<h3>My geeky history</h3>

<p>In some ways, I was very sheltered while growing up in California&rsquo;s San Joaquin valley.  I had my horses, my books, a few friends, and a hugely active imagination.  I was mostly busy in my own world of pretend, but not too much so.  I was an adequate student without trying.  I was somewhat social as well as somewhat athletic.  I was also a voracious reader.  This last was probably what led me to declare myself &ldquo;weird&rdquo; in ninth grade.  I&rsquo;m not sure what I was going for at the time, but in hindsight, I was very right.  It was hard to be interested in elclectic, odd, and alternative things in the area where I grew up, since mainstream culture was almost all that was available.  But libraries were a good friend to me and my active imagination combined with new ideas and worlds and creatures from books allowed me to explore my &ldquo;weirdness&rdquo; or what I now call my geekiness.  As an adult, I moved to the San Francisco Bay Area and eventually to Santa Cruz where I found many other geeky people and interests to pursue.  I discovered Sci Fi/Fantasy conventions, the SCA, gaming, electronics, and so much more.  I worked hard at the local community college getting my core classes out of the way, then transferred to UC Santa Cruz, where I discovered that instead of majoring in programming, I could major in computer engineering, playing with chips, resistors, capacitors, and wiring, while taking programming classes as upper division electives.  So much fun!</p>

<h3>My career so far</h3>

<p>When just beginning my career with computers, there was a huge hiring freeze all through Silicon Valley.  This made finding a programming job very difficult for someone still in college.  I got an opportunity, but it started me on the path of software testing instead of programming.  I was initially a little unsatisfied, but eventually grew to love breaking software.  This satisfied me for a long while.  But eventually it was not enough.  I eventually landed my dream job in testing.  I was working with a product that I respected, with technology I enjoyed, with colleagues that were fun and challenging to work with, creating a product that was making a real difference in the world.  But it was a very small company.  And small companies must grow.  And when small companies grow, they change.  And often, those changes create a culture and a company mission that was not what it once was.  Parting with my dream job in the end was painful and made me quesion myself, my abilities, and my passion in technology entirely.  I spent that next year pursuing interests around my family and my horses in order to recover, since I was in no condition to market myself to a new company.  I eventually found my balance again, updated and polished up the ole resume, and dove into the job search.  I was ready to return to work.  I thought.  But as the weeks and then months passed, none of the job listings seemed right.  They were looking for skills I neither had nor wanted, or were working on things that held no interest.  I felt my passion for technology falling to the wayside, in the face of the drab, the mundane, the stultifying.  It was a low moment indeed.</p>

<p>Thus begins my journey.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Family summer vacation]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/20/family-summer-vacation/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-20T22:37:45-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/20/family-summer-vacation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>July 17-21, 2013</p>

<h3>Family vacation</h3>

<p>Something I haven&rsquo;t been mentioning too much yet is the importance of taking time for yourself and for your family.  It can be a lot of effort in logistics and preparation, but going away with my family and putting most of our every day responsibilities aside for a time can be a wonderful way to relax and reconnect.</p>

<h3>Summer camp</h3>

<p>Some of the family is involved in a martial art.  The art has a summer camp every year that is an extended weekend campout at a beautiful lake on the Olympic peninsula.  The participants organize into little workshops or hikes on the days leading up to the last day when all gather for the summer Belt Test.</p>

<h3>Family time</h3>

<p>I am fortunate that this is an event that is looked forward to by the whole family.  We keep it pretty civilized though by staying in an RV.  We like our hot showers and easy cooking facilities, not to mention the espresso machine and power for our devices.  I mean really, how would I blog without power?  Still, much of the time is spent together around the campfire, swimming, hiking, or playing games.</p>

<h3>Mostly peaceful</h3>

<p>The weather was lovely.  The company was good.  Swimming in the lake was divine.  Our little boy had such a good time, with a possible exception of one late night when his tummy decided ENOUGH!.  Ah well, I managed to get Everything cleaned up in the Rented RV after only 2 or 3 hours.  Poor little guy.  Poor mama.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code Fellows accepts my preliminary application]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/10/code-fellows-accepts-my-preliminary-application/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-10T20:50:02-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/02/10/code-fellows-accepts-my-preliminary-application</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>August 1st, 2013</p>

<h3>Code sample</h3>

<p>Code sample nearly complete.  I&rsquo;ve been checking into github all along the way.  It makes me feel a bit vulnerable to put the code out there while I&rsquo;m still working on it, but I will wait until I finish before I submit it officially.  Perhaps seeing how I put it together will give them more of a good impression that not.  I hope so.  I find myself being quite self conscious of my code.  My husband asked to take a look at it and has been pouring through it all afternoon&hellip;talk about self consciouness inducing.  Whew!</p>

<h3>Guessing my level</h3>

<p>I am very interested to see if I will qualify for the Silver or the Gold level of boot camp.  Gold means that I can skip the first month-long class and just take the second one.  It will be a lovely savings in time and money, so I am doing my best and we&rsquo;ll see how I rank.  The savings would be nice, but I am more interested in finding out where I place.  I find that sort of metric to be very interesting.  I&rsquo;m guessing that I rank about week 3 of 4 in the first month.  That would still mean that I need to take the first class too, but I&rsquo;ll have a very thorough review for the first week or so.  All to the good.  I could use a good portfolio of code snippets I&rsquo;ve written stored up on github for those code submissions that I&rsquo;ve been told companies are more interested in these days.</p>

<h3>Coding at the lake</h3>

<p>I had a lovely afternoon early this week having a picnic at Rattlesnake Lake with son, husband, and friend.  Perfect weather, not too hot, not too cold.  The others frolicked in the water, as I sat in the shade working out some snarls in my code.  Got all the code fixed that was broken.  Implemented additional code, some even worked right off.  All is unit tested.  Happy family.  Happy mama.</p>

<h3>Blueberries!</h3>

<p>Took another break yesterday morning to take son, husband, and friend blueberry picking at the local farm.  We came home with 16 pounds!  Reaped wonderful rewards at 2am while burning the midnight oil coding, as the smell of blueberry crumble wafted upstairs from the ambitious efforts of my brother&rsquo;s girlfriend.  Oh joy!  The merits of diligence to my work as well as taking time with my family.  I must be doing something right.</p>

<h3>Wrapup</h3>

<p>And now it is time to get back to figuring out that intro video.  I&rsquo;m taking a break from the code for the moment.  I&rsquo;ve done a lot over the last 24 hours, so I should give it a little bit of a rest before I leap in and implement that UI.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Ready for Bootcamp]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/30/getting-ready-for-bootcamp/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-30T20:56:47-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/30/getting-ready-for-bootcamp</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>September 16th, 2013</p>

<p>The news has finally come.  I have been accepted to both silver and gold.  I am excited, pleased, terrified, and eager.  I am torn between wishing I&rsquo;d been qualified to skip silver and go straight to gold.  It would have been a nice time and money saver.  I am also relieved, in that now I know I will be fully qualified as I start each class and won&rsquo;t be running to catch up a little as I go straight into gold.  Additional huge bonus for me will be attending both bootcamps at the same time as my husband.  Sharing the commute and sharing the experience together will be, I think, a great benefit for us both.</p>

<p>Now is the big push to try to get the blog launched before bootcamp starts in exactly 3 weeks.  This, on top of getting the ranch ready for the rainy season, mostly this means spreading the contents of the compost bins on the pasture before the rain shuts down that process for the season.  Additionally, I seem to have gotten it into my head to freeze and can fruits and sauces this year. I&rsquo;ve been having fun experimenting with my new canning skills.  Thank you again to good friends who held a Jam Bee where an experienced friend taught us how to make and can berry jam.  This gives me a nice way to store my husband&rsquo;s yummy spaghetti sauce made with roma tomatoes from my garden.  I feel very domestic and accomplished.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll enjoy having the time for these sorts of endeavors of love for my family while I am able.  Soon enough, I&rsquo;ll be taking care of my family using different talents.  It will be nice this winter, when I am thoroughly re-immersed in the working world, to be able to pull out some of those tasty summer offerings tucked away on a shelf, brimming with flavors from the sun.  I never really thought of myself as the back to
nature, hippy type.  But I do love feeding my family so well with local produce.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Day Before Code Fellows Starts]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/25/day-before-code-fellows-starts/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-25T10:35:29-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2013/12/25/day-before-code-fellows-starts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>October 6th, 2013</p>

<p>Very nervous today.  CodeFellows starts tomorrow.  I&rsquo;m working out my nerves by thoroughly clearning several rooms in the house, knowing that this sort of thing will fall by the wayside for the next two months.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve got my laptop backed up, upgraded to OSX 10.8, and made sure everything still works.</p>

<p>My beloved boy is all sorts of worried and stressed by the changes we&rsquo;ve warned him are coming.</p>

<p>Time to get some good sleep before the adventure starts in the morning.</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
