<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: hardware roots | A Woman's Journey Through Technology]]></title>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/categories/hardware-roots/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-05T15:50:26-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://geekymamamare.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Susan Prestage]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Do I Want]]></title>
    <link href="http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/20/what-do-i-want/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-20T21:19:07-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://geekymamamare.com/blog/2014/04/20/what-do-i-want</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Thanksgiving visit</h3>

<p>An old friend from my old Santa Cruz days visited over Thanksgiving.  I was pretty uncomfortable in my own skin at the time and had been been feeling like I didn&rsquo;t have anyone I felt like I could turn to.</p>

<h3>Turning to others is hard</h3>

<p>You see, I&rsquo;m a very strong personality.  Small surprise there, I know.  But what this ends up meaning is that for all I seem very strong and able on the outside, I have a lot of doubt and weakness on the inside.  I feel like so many people look up to me (I still am perplexed by this), but none of them feel to me like they are strong enough and have the perpective to be someone I can lean one and turn to when I&rsquo;m feeling week and in need of someone who sees me as just a person.  Sees me with my faults and foibles, but loves me deeply and so can give me that support that only a friend who has known you for many years can give you.  The kind of support that sometimes involves a boot in the arse.  Thank you, dear Kallie.</p>

<h3>Rediscovering my geekery</h3>

<p>She reminded me of the things I find important.  And that my weakness was part of my strength and definitely part of my appeal.  She showed me the beginnings of the support that women can give one another.  And I started to discover some of the strength found from the support of other engineering women.  She reminded me, through many delightfully geeky conversations of my love for engineering, right down to the ones and zeros of circuit design.  To be sure I&rsquo;d learned the lesson, this valued friend sent me a LED clock engineering kit for my birthday in the beginning of 2013.  It wasn&rsquo;t very long before I took the time to start soldering the pieces of that clock.  So. Much. Fun.</p>

<p>Hey.  There it is.  My joy in engineering.  Still there, without a doubt.</p>

<p>OK, so now what&hellip;?</p>

<p><br></p>

<center>~ Geeky Mama Mare ~</center>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
